<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wind&amp;bones on Wind&amp;Bones</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/windbones/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wind&amp;bones on Wind&amp;Bones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/windbones/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A New Philosophy Salon in Tainan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/philosophy-salon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/philosophy-salon/</guid>
      <description>Last month, we kicked off our latest project, a philosophy salon in collaboration with the wonderful people at the Wansha Performing Arts Centre / 涴莎藝術展演中心 here in Tainan. The salon is a chance for members of the public to come together and talk about the relationship between philosophy and the paradoxes and puzzles of everyday life.&#xA;We are incredibly excited by this project, in particular because it is our first Chinese-language-only project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wind&amp;Bones in Korea!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-korea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-korea/</guid>
      <description>How can stories, books, museums, and other parts of our shared culture bring about social change? We think about these things a lot, so it&amp;rsquo;s been a delight to be visiting the seaside city of Busan in Korea, where we were at the World Humanities Forum, talking about Humanities in Relationship: Towards Communication, Coexistence and Empathy.&#xA;Wind&amp;amp;Bones&amp;rsquo;s Dr Will Buckingham was presenting a paper at the forum on how the idea of philoxenia — a term coming from Greek meaning &amp;ldquo;friendship with that which is other&amp;rdquo; — can help us think through the significance of museums for their visitors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Dr Tim Hannigan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/credne-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/credne-interview/</guid>
      <description>Two years ago, we recorded this interview with the brilliant travel writer, Dr Tim Hannigan. At the time, Tim was working on the Credne project at Dublin City University, exploring the nature of creativity.&#xA;Tim was a great interviewer: friendly, enthusiastic and astute, and as a result, the interview gives a really good overview of our work at Wind&amp;amp;Bones. The interview below is very lightly edited. Happy reading!&#xA;On creativity Tim Hello, Will and Hannah.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wind&amp;Bones - Looking forward, Looking Back</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/looking-forward-looking-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/looking-forward-looking-back/</guid>
      <description>Happy New Year from Madeira, where we are taking a working break for a couple of weeks. While here in Funchal, we&amp;rsquo;re looking over what we have done in 2022 and making plans for 2023.&#xA;2022 in Review Wind&amp;amp;Bones move to Scotland Last year was incredibly busy. The most significant change was that we moved from Sofia, Bulgaria, to Dundee, Scotland. After almost 2½ years working in Bulgaria, we felt like we needed to reconnect to our UK roots, so we moved up to Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wind&amp;Bones are now based in Dundee!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dundee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dundee/</guid>
      <description>Over the last couple of weeks, we&amp;rsquo;ve been busy moving our headquarters of operations from Sofia in Bulgaria to Dundee in Scotland. We landed here a week ago, and since then, we&amp;rsquo;ve been busy unpacking boxes and getting settled. It&amp;rsquo;s great to be up in Scotland. We&amp;rsquo;ve only been here a few days. But already, Dundee has been hugely welcoming. It has been great to start making connections and getting to know the local writing scene.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking for Wisdom - A New Collaboration for Wind&amp;Bones</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/looking-for-wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/looking-for-wisdom/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re delighted that Looking for Wisdom, the philosophy-by-email project run by Dr Will Buckingham, is now a part of Wind&amp;amp;Bones. At Wind&amp;amp;Bones, we believe that creative writing and creative thinking have the power to change the world. So this new collaboration is a great fit for what we do.&#xA;Looking for Wisdom brings the world&amp;rsquo;s philosophy to your inbox with free weekly Philosopher Files. The project was launched formally on January 1st this year.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
