<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interview on Wind&amp;Bones</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/interview/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interview on Wind&amp;Bones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/interview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Dr Tim Hannigan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/credne-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/credne-interview/</guid>
      <description>Two years ago, we recorded this interview with the brilliant travel writer, Dr Tim Hannigan. At the time, Tim was working on the Credne project at Dublin City University, exploring the nature of creativity.&#xA;Tim was a great interviewer: friendly, enthusiastic and astute, and as a result, the interview gives a really good overview of our work at Wind&amp;amp;Bones. The interview below is very lightly edited. Happy reading!&#xA;On creativity Tim Hello, Will and Hannah.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Dr Tim Hannigan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/southern-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/southern-university/</guid>
      <description>Two years ago, we recorded this interview with the brilliant travel writer, Dr Tim Hannigan. At the time, Tim was working on the Credne project at Dublin City University, exploring the nature of creativity.&#xA;Tim was a great interviewer: friendly, enthusiastic and astute, and as a result, the interview gives a really good overview of our work at Wind&amp;amp;Bones. The interview below is very lightly edited. Happy reading!&#xA;On creativity Tim Hello, Will and Hannah.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creativity on the Margins of Academia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/creativity-margins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/creativity-margins/</guid>
      <description>The other week, we had the pleasure of sitting down for a long Zoom chat about creativity with scholar, travel-writer and researcher Dr Tim Hannigan. Tim works for Dublin City University on their DCU CREDNE — Forging Creativity project.&#xA;We were talking about the connections between creativity and interdisciplinarity, why we want university creative writing to decamp from English departments to the art school, and the creative benefits of operating at the margins of formal academia.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspirations - Maisie Chan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/inspirations-maisie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/inspirations-maisie/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we’re featuring the fabulous Maisie Chan. Read our wide-ranging interview about writing, representation, the ongoing harms of orientalism, and the dedication it takes to be a damn good storyteller.&#xA;Hello, Maisie. It’s great to talk to you. We’re particularly excited because you are the first writer in our Inspirations series, where we feature writers committed to using their words to make the world a better place. This is a really exciting time to be talking to you because you’ve got not one, but two books coming out in the coming few months: Danny Chung Does Not Do Maths (Piccadilly Press), published in the USA as Danny Chung Sums it Up (Amulet Books), and Tiger Warrior: Attack of the Dragon King (Orchard Books).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
