<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Our Projects on 滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Our Projects on 滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wansha Philosophy Salon</title>
      <link>/projects/wansha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/wansha/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2024 Project location: Tainan, Taiwan Project partners: Wansha Performing Arts Centre / 涴莎藝術展演中心 Overview From January 2024 to November 2024, we&amp;rsquo;re running a public philosophy salon at the Wansha Performing Arts Centre in Tainan. The salon meets on the third Saturday of every month, to ask how philosophy can throw light on the puzzles and paradoxes of everyday life.&#xA;The salon is run entirely in Mandarin (which is a fun challenge for us), and is free for the public to attend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dragon-carving for Writers</title>
      <link>/projects/dragon-carving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/dragon-carving/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2023 Project location: Scotland / China Project partners: Dr Sipei Lu, British Council Overview In 2023, we were awarded a Connections Through Culture grant for a pilot project working on cross-cultural creativity. Working with China-based academic and writer Dr Sipei Lu, we are running a workshop for Chinese and English writers, exploring Liu Xie&amp;rsquo;s medieval Chinese classic the Wenxin diaolong (文心雕龍), or The Heart of Literature, the Carving of Dragons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Enduring Questions with the Premise Institute</title>
      <link>/projects/premise-institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/premise-institute/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2023 Project location: UK / USA Project partners: Premise Institute Overview In the spring of 2023, we&amp;rsquo;re partnering with the Premise Institute, based over in the promised land of literature that is Portland, Oregon. Premise is a community &amp;ldquo;where the curious come to connect, learn, and grapple with life’s enduring questions.&amp;rdquo; Premise is neither a book club nor a college-style course. Instead, it is a chance to explore wide-ranging questions about human life, based on the shared experience of reading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After the Coup - Storytelling and Education</title>
      <link>/projects/myanmar-teachers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/myanmar-teachers/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Autumn 2022 Project location: Myanmar / Thailand Overview In the autumn of 2022, we worked with a Myanmar-based NGO and a group of community teachers on a project to develop storytelling skills in the classroom.&#xA;The teachers with whom we worked are continuing to provide education in the difficult post-coup landscape of Myanmar. We ran this project with a Myanmar-based NGO to explore how storytelling can be used as a pedagogical tool.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chance Encounters</title>
      <link>/projects/chance-encounters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/chance-encounters/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Summer 2022 Project location: Wigtown, Scotland Project partners: Wigtown Book Festival Overview In 2023, we were invited to the Wigtown book festival to run a public drop-in writing workshops called Chance Encounters. We invited members of the public to share stories about their own chance encounters, each story determined by a roll of the dice.&#xA;Then put their stories in unmarked envelopes.&#xA;When more passers-by came to share their stories, we gave them a story from one of the sealed envelopes to take away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waterford Harvest Festival Story Farm</title>
      <link>/projects/story-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/story-farm/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Summer 2022 Project location: Waterford, Ireland Project partners: GIY (Ireland) Overview In the summer of 2022, we were invited to Waterford, Ireland to take part in the Waterford Harvest Festival, run by the social enterprise Grow It Yourself (GIY).&#xA;The festival was a festival of food done right. And we were farming stories about food, community, culture and place.&#xA;Project Outcomes Over the course of the weekend, we gathered a huge pile of stories to share with the public, and with GIY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dandelion Festival</title>
      <link>/projects/dandelion-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/dandelion-festival/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Summer 2022 Project location: Glasgow, Scotland Project partners: Unboxed UK, Dandelion Festival. Overview In the summer of 2020, we worked with the Dandelion Festival to delivery three days of workshops with the general public in Kelvingrove Park, Glasgow.&#xA;Dandelion was a festival dedicated to rethinking our relationships with food and growing. We set up in a potting shed in the park, where we spent three intensive days working with members of the public.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Awakening Between the Lines</title>
      <link>/projects/awakening-between-the-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/awakening-between-the-lines/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2022-2023 Project location: Sofia, Bulgaria Project partners: British Embassy, Bulgaria; the Emprove Foundation, Bulgaria. Overview We worked with the Emprove Foundation and British Embassy, Bulgaria, on an innovative project to raise awareness of the issue of domestic abuse. Emprove Foundation work with women survivors of abuse. For this project, we ran a six-week intensive workshop on writing for a group of women survivors.&#xA;The stories were edited into final form and cross-translated between Bulgarian and English.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto for a Regenerative Bioregion, Waterford</title>
      <link>/projects/waterford-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/waterford-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Summer 2022 Project location: Waterford, Ireland Project partners: GIY (Ireland), Dr Sarah Prosser Overview The Bioregional Weaving Labs Collective is an ambitious project of the Ashoka foundation that aims to reweave connections between peoples, communities, cultures and the natural world. Waterford, Ireland, is one of the bioregions that is spearheading this exciting initiative.&#xA;Wind&amp;amp;Bones were invited to co-lead a workshop with Waterford&amp;rsquo;s own &amp;ldquo;weaver&amp;rdquo;, Dr. Sarah Prosser. We worked with local farmers, community members and consumers to write a manifesto for rethinking the centrality of food in our lives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Universe of Stories</title>
      <link>/projects/goethe-institut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/goethe-institut/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: June 2020 Project location: Sofia, Bulgaria Project partners: Goethe Institut, Bulgaria; Caritas, Bulgaria Overview For World Refugee Day in 2020, we ran a day of writing workshops in collaboration with the Goethe Institut, Bulgaria, and Caritas.&#xA;During the workshop, participants shared stories in multiple languages: English, Bulgarian, Kurdish and Arabic. We were aided by Sophia, Caritas&amp;rsquo;s brilliant translator.&#xA;Project Outcomes What we loved about the stories the participants told was how varied they were, how in a few brief hours we mapped out the vastness of human experience: we had funny stories and sad stories, everyday stories and stories about extraordinary events.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenpeace Writers&#39; &amp; Activists&#39; Cafe</title>
      <link>/projects/writers-activists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/writers-activists/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2020 Project location: Sofia, Bulgaria Project partners: Greenpeace, Bulgaria. Overview In 2020, we set up a Writers&amp;rsquo; and Activists&amp;rsquo; café with Greenpeace, Bulgaria. The idea of the café was that we would gather every week in Greenpeace&amp;rsquo;s wonderful community space in the heart of Sofia, and we would explore how writing can be used to bring about positive social change.&#xA;The café was free to access, run on a donation-only basis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethical Leadership with Mote Oo</title>
      <link>/projects/mote-oo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/mote-oo/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2018-2023 Project location: Myanmar Project partners: Mote Oo Education, Myanmar; Payap University, Thailand Overview In 2018, we were commissioned by Mote Oo to write a coursebook on ethical leadership that was sensitive to the needs of community groups, civil society organisations and NGOs in Myanmar.&#xA;We looked around at the material available on ethical leadership, and found it wanting. There were several problems with pre-existing courses:&#xA;They were overly business-focussed, written primarily for the corporate world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Bridges with Paung Ku</title>
      <link>/projects/bulding-bridges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/bulding-bridges/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2019 Project location: Yangon, Myanmar Project partners: Paung Ku, Myanmar. Overview In 2019, we ran a three-day workshop with staff from the Myanmar civil society organisation, Paung Ku, who are an organisation committed to driving positive social change. Paung Khu&amp;rsquo;s vision is of a pluralistic society that values the diversity of ethnicity, culture and belief in Myanmar, and that ensures equity and respect for the rights of all, particularly those who are marginalised.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creative Writing at Volvi</title>
      <link>/projects/volvi-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/volvi-writing/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2019 Project location: Volvi, Greece Project partners: Refugee Trauma Initiative Overview We were invited by the brilliantly innovative NGO, Refugee Trauma Initiative, to run creative writing workshops in Volvi refugee camp, north of Thessaloniki, Greece.&#xA;We worked with a wide variety of young people, telling and sharing stories in multiple languages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto - A workshop and talk</title>
      <link>/projects/manifestos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/manifestos/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2019 Project location: Plovdiv, Bulgaria Project partners: Ideas Factory, Bulgaria Overview We were invited to the 2019 EmpathEAST forum for Empathy-driven Social Change in Plovdiv, Bulgaria to talk about our Wind&amp;amp;Bones work.&#xA;The three-day forum was a gathering of social activists, changemakers, artists and academics, all interested in exploring the ways in which it might be possible to bring about positive social change.&#xA;We gave a talk to the delegates (see the link below) and ran our first ever manifesto-writing workshop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writers in Residence at The Parami Institute</title>
      <link>/projects/parami-residency/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/parami-residency/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2018-2019 Project location: Yangon, Myanmar Project partners: The Parami Institute, Myanmar Overview Between 2018 and 2019, we were writers in residence at the Parami Institute in Yangon, Myanmar. We ran a series of public-facing writing workshops, with a focus on writing for social change.&#xA;We worked with a diverse group of students: NGO workers, doctors, former political prisoners, community radio hosts, journalists, writers, activists and many more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Write Here - Writing for Refugees</title>
      <link>/projects/write-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/write-here/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Summer 2017 Project location: Leicester, England Project partners: Writing East Midlands, Leicester City of Sanctuary Overview This was our very first project: a series of workshops with refugee writers in the city of Leicester. We decided when we set up the workshops that we wanted them to be about writing and storytelling, rather than English-language classes. So we made the decision that we would encourage writers to write in whatever language they felt comfortable.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
