<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>故事 | Stories on 滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 故事 | Stories on 滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vegan Heaven</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/2025-03-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/2025-03-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We were an Ecuadorian city man, a mountain llama farmer, four Americans and one Brit wild hiking all day at about 4,000 metres elevation. I was cooking our evening meal, and suspicion was everywhere. It was vegan. An Indian curry. They saw with alarm the fruit being added to the veg: ripe bananas, apple, sultanas. Plus a handful of cashew nuts. This has to be bad!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then they tasted it. &lt;em&gt;Heaven&lt;/em&gt;. Not a scrap left, and the story became part of our hiking community legends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An acquired taste</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/2024-06-11-an-acquired-taste/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 03:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/2024-06-11-an-acquired-taste/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to local snacks in Taiwan, stinky tofu will definitely come to mind, but is it a mouth-watering delicacy, or is it a disgusting food that smells like stinking ditches?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think that although stinky tofu is pungent and unpleasant, the crispy skin paired with pickled cabbage and sauce is simply delicious the moment you put it in your mouth. The streets of Tainan are full of such affordable delicacies that make you want to try again and again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dumplings</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/2024-06-11-dumplings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/2024-06-11-dumplings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When my clan was still intact, my grandpa was still alive, my dad and uncle had not yet broken up their affection, my family always had a big meal on Chinese New Year. This feast was the one I most looked forward to every year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dumplings are the food which best represent home. Dumplings are a dish that everyone in the family learned how to cook: my grandma, dad, mom, my elder brother and sister, and me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Sweet Potato</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/2024-06-11-sweet-sweet-potato/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/2024-06-11-sweet-sweet-potato/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid, on major holidays like Mother&amp;rsquo;s Day, our family would go to a barbecue restaurant to enjoy a big meal . The meat was good quality, fresh and juicy, but the most unforgettable thing about it was the taste. And the the sweet potato, filled with cheese cream.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The salty cheese and the sweetness of the sweet potato was simply a feast!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— Natalie&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wrapping Zongzi</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/2024-05-25-zongzi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/2024-05-25-zongzi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a big foodie, so I frequently fall in love with food. And of all the foods I have ever eaten, &lt;em&gt;zongzi&lt;/em&gt; is the best. Before the annual Dragon Boat Festival comes,  my grandmother is always busy. She needs to wrap over two hundred &lt;em&gt;zongzi&lt;/em&gt; for my family and friends. As she wraps them, she patiently teaches me. It&amp;rsquo;s a technical challenge to wrap them perfectly and quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inside the &lt;em&gt;zongzi&lt;/em&gt; are sticky rice, peanuts, marinated pork, and dried shrimp. And in every batch, there is only one with a salted egg yolk. The one with the yolk is valuable. It is a sign of good fortune.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oyster Omelette</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/oyster-omelette/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/oyster-omelette/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think the food that makes me most homesick is oyster omelette. For me, the reason Oyster Omelette is special is because this the first time my mother cooked anything other than poached eggs together, this is what we cooked.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although it looks terrible, it nevertheless tastes delicious. I like it a lot, but it also brings me valuable memories with my mom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— &lt;strong&gt;Michelle, National Tainan Chia Chi Senior High School 國立臺南家齊高級中等學校&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stinky Tofu</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/stinky-tofu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/stinky-tofu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I believe the most delicious food in the world is stinky tofu. Hot tofu surrounded by crispy skin — and when you bite into it with kimchi, it is really a treat!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I could only choose  one dish in the world to accompany me for the rest of my life, then I would choose stinky tofu.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— &lt;strong&gt;Jenny, National Tainan Chia Chi Senior High School 國立臺南家齊高級中等學校&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Website Updates</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/website-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/website-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we started this website, it was just a small project for our residency at the Nanning Literature House in December 2023. But since then, there has been a lot of interest from people wanting to share their stories. So we thought it was time we gave the website a bit of a new look.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re still finishing off our refurbishment, so some things may still not work perfectly, but we like the new colour scheme and typography. We&amp;rsquo;ve got a bunch of new stories to upload as well, from our recent visit to the National Tainan Chia Chi Senior High School 國立臺南家齊高級中等學校 , so keep your eyes peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ginger Duck Hotpot</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/duck-hotpot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/duck-hotpot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my most cherished meals is pork blood cake in ginger duck hot pot. The rich flavors of the cake blend perfectly with the fragrant sesame oil-infused broth. Despite Taiwan&amp;rsquo;s lack of distinct winters, I love sharing this dish with my family, creating treasured memories.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Image: From A Natural History of Ducks (1922). Public domain via &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:A_natural_history_of_the_ducks_(1922)_(14583073697).jpg&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Banquet of Stories</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/banquet-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/banquet-stories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two days before Christmas, we wrapped up our project with a final lecture generously hosted by the StableNice Café here in Tainan. We drank tea, ate cake, talked about our work at Wind&amp;amp;Bones, shared some of the stories from the project, and talked about what we had learned over the ten days of our residency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We also spent some time encouraging guests to get involved by sharing stories of their own. This made for a wonderfully moving afternoon — a shared feast of stories, food and friendship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pork Braised Rice</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/pork-braised/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/pork-braised/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to eating something special, I think of nothing but pork braised rice. Why? Because my mum is really good at cooking it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pork braised rice always brings me warm and happy memories. The colour, the smell, the taste — it always arouses my appetite.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wherever I am, I cannot forget pork braised rice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-william-liu&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;— William Liu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image: Office of the President, &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Via &lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/9f/12.17_%E7%B8%BD%E7%B5%B1%E9%82%80%E8%AB%8B%E5%9C%8B%E4%BA%BA%E5%8A%A0%E5%85%A5%E8%B1%AC%E7%98%9F%E9%98%B2%E7%96%AB%E5%A4%A7%E4%BD%9C%E6%88%B0_(44543856860).jpg/1024px-12.17_%E7%B8%BD%E7%B5%B1%E9%82%80%E8%AB%8B%E5%9C%8B%E4%BA%BA%E5%8A%A0%E5%85%A5%E8%B1%AC%E7%98%9F%E9%98%B2%E7%96%AB%E5%A4%A7%E4%BD%9C%E6%88%B0_(44543856860).jpg&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>一股連我也不知道是什麼的滋味 | A flavour even I don&#39;t know</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/strange-flavour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/strange-flavour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;一股連我也不知道是什麼的滋味從裡向外展開&#34;&gt;一股連我也不知道是什麼的滋味，從裡向外展開&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;我會注意到那攤子，是因為所有人似乎都急切的想要無視它。賣仙草茶的老人衝著行人笑，笑的有點不知所措。&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;我拉著媽直直走向攤子。「一杯！」&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;老人怔了怔才把茶給我。過時的東西賣久了，連他也差點無視了自己的存在。我喝了一口沒人要的茶。苦！&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;「好喝嗎？」我媽遲疑地問。&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;「我們買一瓶回家！」老人笑開了花。&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;我又喝了一口。&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;— Kelly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-flavour-even-i-dont-know&#34;&gt;A flavour even I don&amp;rsquo;t know&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A flavour — even I don&amp;rsquo;t know what it is — unfolds from the inside outwards.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reason I noticed the stall was because everyone else seemed eager to ignore it. The old man selling grass jelly tea smiled at passersby. His smile seemed a little awkward.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I pulled my mum straight towards the stall. &amp;ldquo;Just one cup!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Down the Generations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/down-the-generations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 01:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/down-the-generations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was my father who taught me to cook. In my family he prepared meals for all of us — breakfast, lunch and dinner. This is very different from a traditional Asian family.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reason my father started to cook was because he wanted to reproduce the dishes made by his father, our grandpa. My father&amp;rsquo;s father passed away in my father&amp;rsquo;s early childhood. I never knew him.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since learning why my father cooked, I have asked him to teach me some basic cooking skills. It&amp;rsquo;s so important to preserve the taste of our own home-cooked meals, to pass them down the generations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In a Foreign Land</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/foreign-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/foreign-land/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After arriving in Tokyo a year ago, my cooking skills have noticeably improved. Since being here I&amp;rsquo;ve grown accustomed to the high prices of fruits and gradually accepted the limited variety of vegetables. These new restraints have meant I’ve grown in creativity in the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The excellent quality of beef here is impressive though finding a whole beef shank can be quite difficult. Even when cooking for family, Japanese people seldom buy such large cuts of meat in one go. Thus, when I make braised beef, I often feel a hint of regret: it’s so tasty and I always want more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwanese Kimchi</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/taiwanese-kimchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/taiwanese-kimchi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My grandmother once told me that in her childhood she thought that Taiwanese kimchi was the most delicious food. When I was a child, she told me a bedside story about her early life. She told me how, in the early days of Taiwan, families with farming backgrounds faced financial struggles. They relied on thin porridge with a few small, pickled dried fish, or soy sauce. They rarely had the opportunity to enjoy dishes with meat or vegetables.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tomatoes</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/tomato-fried-egg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/tomato-fried-egg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The tomato is a strange thing, because some call it a vegetable and some think it is a fruit. But to me, whether fruit or vegetable, above all else it is a memory of my childhood.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was small I used to go to the farm near my home to help harvest tomatoes. When we finished the work we each took a tomato and we squeezed it between our palms as a way of cleaning our hands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>不想破壞驚喜｜Not Wanting to Spoil the Surprise</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/surprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/surprise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;不想破壞驚喜&#34;&gt;不想破壞驚喜&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;如果你來到台南， 我非常建議你來富農街、裕農路尋找美食。 在這後甲圓環一帶充滿各式小吃： 火雞肉飯、臭豆腐、鱔魚意麵 ⋯⋯&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;我不能再更多了， 這會破壞驚喜。&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— 張芳瑋&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;not-wanting-to-spoil-the-surprise&#34;&gt;Not Wanting to Spoil the Surprise&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you come to Taiwan, I really recommend you go to Funong Street and Yunong Road, in search of good things to eat. The area by the Houjia roundabout is full of different kinds of snacks: turkey rice, stinky tofu, eel noodles&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t add any more — it will spoil the surprise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>蘿蔔 ｜ Radish</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/radish/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/radish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;蘿蔔&#34;&gt;蘿蔔&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;蘿蔔是台式食物的基本班底。 是低調溫潤的和聲。蘿蔔糕、蘿蔔絲餅、蘿蔔飯、雞湯、蔬菜湯、醃蘿蔔， 可以柔軟也能爽脆。大概是最台南的食材之一，無處不在。&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;– 魚果&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;radish&#34;&gt;Radish&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Radish is the fundamental ingredient of Taiwanese food. It is a subdued and gentle harmony. Radish cake, grated radish patties, radish rice, chicken soup, vegetable soup, pickled radish&amp;hellip; it can be soft and it can be crispy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is perhaps one of ingredients that is most ubiquitous in Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;– Yuguo&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image: The Daikon and the Baby by Helen Hyde. Public domain via &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:The_daikon_and_the_baby_-_Helen_Hyde.jpg.&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>我媽媽的越南菜 | My Mother&#39;s Vietnamese Food</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/vietnamese-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 05:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/vietnamese-food/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;我媽媽的越南菜&#34;&gt;我媽媽的越南菜&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;我的母親來自越南， 所以 當我吃到河粉、法國麵包（越南）、越南春捲時，我就會想起媽媽， 我甚至會去比較， 誰做得比較好吃。&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;不過並不是拿我媽做參考，我媽沒有做過河粉給我吃過。或是說：我沒有印象，可能有。反倒是她常做春捲、雞肉稀飯、生菜沙拉。 這三樣沒人能贏過她。&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;***— 張芳瑋 ***&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-mothers-vietnamese-food&#34;&gt;My Mother&amp;rsquo;s Vietnamese Food&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My mother is from Vietnam, so when I eat &lt;em&gt;phở&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;bánh mì&lt;/em&gt;, or Vietnamese spring rolls, I think of my mum. I even compare who makes them the best. But I don&amp;rsquo;t use my mum as a reference, because my mother has never made me &lt;em&gt;phở&lt;/em&gt; to eat. Or, to put it another way, I don&amp;rsquo;t have any recollection of it, but perhaps she did.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Complicated Relationship</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/complicated-relationship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/complicated-relationship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a complicated relationship with chai. Kenyan chai, not the Indian version. The milk is warmed first, before the water, the tea-dust — fragrant Kenyan tea from the Rift Valley highlands —, and the sugar are all added. It is all done by eye. I have never met a family who follows a recipe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chai is what we serve to guests. It is the first thing we have in the morning, and probably the last thing we have before sleeping. It smells of community, of home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grandmother&#39;s dishes</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/grandmothers-dishes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/grandmothers-dishes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember my grandmother as both affectionate and strict. She had a tough exterior but a soft heart, and she expressed her love in every action. She never said the words, &amp;ldquo;I love you,&amp;rdquo; but everything she did was an embodiment of love.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Her love manifested in numerous ways — holding hands while crossing the street, the small lamp guiding me home after evening classes, the late-night bowl of noodles when we were hungry, the shell-less shrimp she prepared, the adhesive bandage that appeared instantly when I got hurt, and the scolding when I was careless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grandpa&#39;s Stewed Pork Rice</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/grandpas-stewed-pork-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/grandpas-stewed-pork-rice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The food I like most is made by my grandpa. He used to make stewed pork rice (滷肉飯), one of the most famous dishes on Taiwanese dining tables. Every time I got home, the smell always made me happy and joyful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now grandpa is a  sick, so it is our turn to cook for him. Although we can&amp;rsquo;t make our stewed pork rice taste the same as grandpa&amp;rsquo;s, I still think it is delicious: it is one of the most delicious dishes of all. I hope that grandpa thinks the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turnip Cake</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/turnip-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/turnip-cake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Turnip cake (in Taiwanese, 菜頭粿 tshài-thâu-ké) is a staple of Taiwanese breakfast shops. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those comfort foods that is comforting because of its very simplicity. Taiwanese friends have told us that when they are elsewhere in the world, the thought of tshài-thâu-ké makes them go weak at the knees with nostalgia.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But if breakfast shop turnip cake is good, home-cooked turnip cake is so much better. So here&amp;rsquo;s a little story in Chinese from our afternoon tea workshop, about grandma&amp;rsquo;s home-cooked tshài-thâu-ké.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afternoon Tea</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/afternoon-tea-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/afternoon-tea-event/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday we held our &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/afternoon-tea&#34;&gt;afternoon tea&lt;/a&gt; event here at the Nanning Literary House. We designed this as an informal writing workshop, inviting friends and strangers into the literary house to eat home-made scones (we were busy all Sunday morning in the kitchen!), and to share stories about food.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We asked our visitors to write their stories — in English, Chinese, or any language they chose — on small cards, and we hung these outside the literary house for passers-by to read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pasta al Carbonara</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/pasta-al-carbonara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/pasta-al-carbonara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My memories of carbonara are so rich and deep. It will always be my go-to food, until the day I die.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everything started when I was a kid, and my mum used to cook carbonara for me, because it&amp;rsquo;s fast and cheap. Every Wednesday, she would pick us up at school and bring us back home to have lunch with her during her break. My brother and I would eat with her. For the rest of the week, we would wait impatiently for Wednesday, when we could skip the school restaurant (it always tasted so bad) to have mum&amp;rsquo;s wonderful pasta. It came with the good vibes and joyful atmosphere my mum brings everywhere she goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweet and Sour Mulberries</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/mulberries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/mulberries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No matter where I am, no matter how old I am, whenever I see mulberries I think of home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The story began 50 years ago. As a child, I had lots of time for leisure activities. I climbed trees to pick fruit, played baseball and played marbles. But picking mulberries is the thing I remember most. Why? Because it was a chance for me, my cousins and my neighbors to get closer and share secrets and dreams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blue Eyes</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/blue-eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/blue-eyes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the waitress began to speak, I looked closely at her face, and I noticed that she had the most unusual eyes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think she wore contact lenses because her eyes were blue, but not a crystal-like, light blue like I usually see at home: they were deep navy, almost purple. And I&amp;rsquo;d never seen eyes like that before.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— Hannah Stevens&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cat Cake</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/cat-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 05:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/cat-cake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We were walking home late one evening when I saw it. It was a white sign with black writing that read &amp;lsquo;Cake&amp;rsquo; in English.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There was the image of a cat on the sign and the cat wore sunglasses. As we got closer I could smell the cake. It smelled of cooked sugar, beaten eggs, creamed butter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We didn&amp;rsquo;t stop there that night but I want to go back.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— Hannah Stevens&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culinary Heaven</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/culinary-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 05:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/culinary-heaven/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tainan is a culinary heaven. It flourishes with lively, historic flavours. Every dish echoes the city&amp;rsquo;s rich heritage. Food in Tainan is a vibrant fusion of tradition and innovation on the taste buds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Waking up in the morning, have a bowl of hot beef soup from the market, or a soul-soothing bowl of tender minced pork, to make you feel energetic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After work in the morning, have a milkfish feast, especially the belly and skin. The owners of the fish shop will clean the skins and the entrails, and add onions and ginger so you can just open your mouth and eat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Custard Tart</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/custard-tart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/custard-tart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The custard tarts are deep, soft, still warm from the oven. We just bought them from a stall down the road.  We take them from their ruffled paper cake-cups, bite in to them, slowly, carefully. The pastry crumbles. The custard is sweet and creamy. We eat them up in five bites.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image by Paul Klee (1921): &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Where_the_Eggs_and_the_Good_Roast_Come_From_MET_DT5836.jpg&#34;&gt;Public domain via Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fried Bao</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/fried-bao/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/fried-bao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;fried-bao&#34;&gt;Fried Bao&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I get to the fried bao stall too late. &amp;ldquo;Sold out,&amp;rdquo; the boss tells me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next day, I am up extra early. When I arrive at the fried bao stall, the boss looks pleased. Some of these foreigners learn fast. &amp;ldquo;Today,&amp;rdquo; she says, &amp;ldquo;you have come on time&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I buy six. To celebrate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;--will-buckingham&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Will Buckingham&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;煎包&#34;&gt;煎包&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;當我到達煎包攤車的時候，已經太晚了。老闆娘對我說：「賣光了！」&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;第二天，我比較早起床。當我到達煎包攤車時，老闆娘看起來很滿意。有些外國人學得很快。她說：「今天準時來了！」&#xA;我買了六個，為了慶祝。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tasty Things</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/tasty-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/tasty-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At dinner, we eat fish, and pork with strips of salted ginger, and water spinach. It is the first day of our residency, and we are celebrating with a beer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The table next door is boisterous. There&amp;rsquo;s a large group of customers drinking whiskey. They are talking loudly in Taiwanese. I have become used to the sounds of the language. It feels familiar, even though I can only understand snippets. &amp;ldquo;Guá kā lí kóng&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;I tell you&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;. &amp;ldquo;Guá kám-kak&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;I think&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; They are trading opinions about friends and colleagues and neighbours. They laugh loud, shake their heads at human foolishness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>給我們講一個故事! Tell us a story!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/tell-us-a-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/tell-us-a-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;你吃過最美味的一餐是什麼？有什麼食物讓你想起家鄉？是誰教你做飯的？您是否因為美食而墜入愛河？&lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/contact&#34;&gt;分享你的故事&lt;/a&gt;，我們將在網站上刊登我們最喜歡的故事！&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is the best meal you have ever eaten? What food makes you think of home? Who taught you to cook? Have you ever fallen in love because of food? &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/contact&#34;&gt;Share your stories&lt;/a&gt; and we&amp;rsquo;ll feature our favorites on the site!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;style&gt;&#xA;    div.gallery {&#xA;       display: flex;&#xA;       flex-wrap: wrap;&#xA;    }&#xA;    div.gallery a {&#xA;        flex-grow: 1;&#xA;        object-fit: cover;&#xA;        margin: 2px;&#xA;        display: flex;&#xA;    }&#xA;    div.gallery a img {            &#xA;        height: 200px;&#xA;        object-fit: cover;&#xA;        flex-grow: 1;&#xA;    }  &#xA;    &lt;/style&gt;&#xA;    &lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/fancyapps/fancybox@3.5.7/dist/jquery.fancybox.min.css&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving In</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/fine-dining/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/fine-dining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This morning, we packed our bags and moved across town to Nanning Street, where we are going to be spending the next ten days in the literature house.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve given our residency the title 滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan. We like the idea of writing as an activity that can nourish us. And we&amp;rsquo;re intending to make use of this residency to nourish our own writing, and to explore the idea of nourishment more broadly. Our plan is to bring together food, stories and everyday philosophy - because food nourishes the body, stories nourish the spirit, and philosophy nourishes the mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Egg Pancakes</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/egg-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/egg-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What could be better, first thing in the morning, than an egg pancake (蛋餅) from one of your favourite local breakfast shops? One of the perpetual dilemmas of living in Tainan is &lt;em&gt;where to eat breakfast&lt;/em&gt;. It is a good dilemma to have. Here in the South District, we have an abundance of options: congee (粥), bao buns (包子), pot-stickers (國鐵), soft wraps (潤餅), egg pancakes (蛋餅)&amp;hellip; Or else, if we remember in time, we put a loaf of sourdough on to rise overnight, and when we get up, we stick it in our new box oven so that by breakfast time, the house is filled with the smell of baking bread.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Nourishing Tainan!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/hello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello， 大家好 and ta̍k-ke hó!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a Friday morning, and we&amp;rsquo;re starting to feel very excited about our residency starting next Wednesday. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to do before then (we need to make some more plans, we need to buy a teapot, we need to read some more), but by Wednesday, we&amp;rsquo;ll be installed in the Nanning Literature House (南寧文學·家), ready to explore the food, stories and everyday-life philosophy of Tainan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
