<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>故事 | Stories on 滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 故事 | Stories on 滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 01:15:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Down the Generations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/down-the-generations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 01:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/down-the-generations/</guid>
      <description>It was my father who taught me to cook. In my family he prepared meals for all of us — breakfast, lunch and dinner. This is very different from a traditional Asian family.&#xA;The reason my father started to cook was because he wanted to reproduce the dishes made by his father, our grandpa. My father&amp;rsquo;s father passed away in my father&amp;rsquo;s early childhood. I never knew him.&#xA;Since learning why my father cooked, I have asked him to teach me some basic cooking skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In a Foreign Land</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/foreign-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/foreign-land/</guid>
      <description>After arriving in Tokyo a year ago, my cooking skills have noticeably improved. Since being here I&amp;rsquo;ve grown accustomed to the high prices of fruits and gradually accepted the limited variety of vegetables. These new restraints have meant I’ve grown in creativity in the kitchen.&#xA;The excellent quality of beef here is impressive though finding a whole beef shank can be quite difficult. Even when cooking for family, Japanese people seldom buy such large cuts of meat in one go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwanese Kimchi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/taiwanese-kimchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/taiwanese-kimchi/</guid>
      <description>My grandmother once told me that in her childhood she thought that Taiwanese kimchi was the most delicious food. When I was a child, she told me a bedside story about her early life. She told me how, in the early days of Taiwan, families with farming backgrounds faced financial struggles. They relied on thin porridge with a few small, pickled dried fish, or soy sauce. They rarely had the opportunity to enjoy dishes with meat or vegetables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>我媽媽的越南菜 | My Mother&#39;s Vietnamese Food</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vietnamese-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 05:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vietnamese-food/</guid>
      <description>我媽媽的越南菜 我的母親來自越南， 所以 當我吃到河粉、法國麵包（越南）、越南春捲時，我就會想起媽媽， 我甚至會去比較， 誰做得比較好吃。&#xA;不過並不是拿我媽做參考，我媽沒有做過河粉給我吃過。或是說：我沒有印象，可能有。反倒是她常做春捲、雞肉稀飯、生菜沙拉。 這三樣沒人能贏過她。&#xA;***— 張芳瑋 ***&#xA;My Mother&amp;rsquo;s Vietnamese Food My mother is from Vietnam, so when I eat phở, bánh mì, or Vietnamese spring rolls, I think of my mum. I even compare who makes them the best. But I don&amp;rsquo;t use my mum as a reference, because my mother has never made me phở to eat. Or, to put it another way, I don&amp;rsquo;t have any recollection of it, but perhaps she did.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Complicated Relationship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/complicated-relationship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/complicated-relationship/</guid>
      <description>I have a complicated relationship with chai. Kenyan chai, not the Indian version. The milk is warmed first, before the water, the tea-dust — fragrant Kenyan tea from the Rift Valley highlands —, and the sugar are all added. It is all done by eye. I have never met a family who follows a recipe.&#xA;Chai is what we serve to guests. It is the first thing we have in the morning, and probably the last thing we have before sleeping.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blue Eyes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blue-eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blue-eyes/</guid>
      <description>When the waitress began to speak, I looked closely at her face, and I noticed that she had the most unusual eyes.&#xA;I think she wore contact lenses because her eyes were blue, but not a crystal-like, light blue like I usually see at home: they were deep navy, almost purple. And I&amp;rsquo;d never seen eyes like that before.&#xA;— Hannah Stevens</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cat Cake</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cat-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 05:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cat-cake/</guid>
      <description>We were walking home late one evening when I saw it. It was a white sign with black writing that read &amp;lsquo;Cake&amp;rsquo; in English.&#xA;There was the image of a cat on the sign and the cat wore sunglasses. As we got closer I could smell the cake. It smelled of cooked sugar, beaten eggs, creamed butter.&#xA;We didn&amp;rsquo;t stop there that night but I want to go back.&#xA;— Hannah Stevens</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culinary Heaven</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/culinary-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 05:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/culinary-heaven/</guid>
      <description>Tainan is a culinary heaven. It flourishes with lively, historic flavours. Every dish echoes the city&amp;rsquo;s rich heritage. Food in Tainan is a vibrant fusion of tradition and innovation on the taste buds.&#xA;Waking up in the morning, have a bowl of hot beef soup from the market, or a soul-soothing bowl of tender minced pork, to make you feel energetic.&#xA;After work in the morning, have a milkfish feast, especially the belly and skin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grandmother&#39;s dishes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-12-19-grandmother/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-12-19-grandmother/</guid>
      <description>I remember my grandmother as both affectionate and strict. She had a tough exterior but a soft heart, and she expressed her love in every action. She never said the words, &amp;ldquo;I love you,&amp;rdquo; but everything she did was an embodiment of love.&#xA;Her love manifested in numerous ways — holding hands while crossing the street, the small lamp guiding me home after evening classes, the late-night bowl of noodles when we were hungry, the shell-less shrimp she prepared, the adhesive bandage that appeared instantly when I got hurt, and the scolding when I was careless.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grandpa&#39;s Stewed Pork Rice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/grandpas-stewed-pork-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/grandpas-stewed-pork-rice/</guid>
      <description>The food I like most is made by my grandpa. He used to make stewed pork rice (滷肉飯), one of the most famous dishes on Taiwanese dining tables. Every time I got home, the smell always made me happy and joyful.&#xA;Now grandpa is a sick, so it is our turn to cook for him. Although we can&amp;rsquo;t make our stewed pork rice taste the same as grandpa&amp;rsquo;s, I still think it is delicious: it is one of the most delicious dishes of all.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
