<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wind&amp;Bones</title>
    <link>https://www.windandbones.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wind&amp;Bones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.windandbones.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A New Philosophy Salon in Tainan</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/philosophy-salon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/philosophy-salon/</guid>
      <description>Last month, we kicked off our latest project, a philosophy salon in collaboration with the wonderful people at the Wansha Performing Arts Centre / 涴莎藝術展演中心 here in Tainan. The salon is a chance for members of the public to come together and talk about the relationship between philosophy and the paradoxes and puzzles of everyday life.&#xA;We are incredibly excited by this project, in particular because it is our first Chinese-language-only project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wansha Philosophy Salon</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/wansha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/wansha/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2024 Project location: Tainan, Taiwan Project partners: Wansha Performing Arts Centre / 涴莎藝術展演中心 Overview From January 2024 to November 2024, we&amp;rsquo;re running a public philosophy salon at the Wansha Performing Arts Centre in Tainan. The salon meets on the third Saturday of every month, to ask how philosophy can throw light on the puzzles and paradoxes of everyday life.&#xA;The salon is run entirely in Mandarin (which is a fun challenge for us), and is free for the public to attend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/%E6%BB%8B%E9%A4%8A%E5%8F%B0%E5%8D%97-nourishing-tainan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 10:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/%E6%BB%8B%E9%A4%8A%E5%8F%B0%E5%8D%97-nourishing-tainan/</guid>
      <description>We ended 2023 with a ten-day residency at the Nanning Literary House (南寧文學·家), where we ran a project called 滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan. We spent ten days working on our writing, and also working with members of the public to write stories about the things that nourish us: the food that nourishes our bodies, the stories that nourish our spirit, and the ideas that nourish our imagination. You can see the project website here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Entrepreneurship at Taitung University</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/social-entrepreneurship-at-taitung-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 02:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/social-entrepreneurship-at-taitung-university/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week, Wind&amp;amp;Bones were in the wonderfully laid-back city of Taitung, where we were invited to give a talk at 國立臺東大學 National Taitung University on social entrepreneurship. It was also the first time we have talked publicly about our work in Chinese, which was very exciting (and not a little nerve-wracking).&#xA;During the lecture, we discussed our work at Wind&amp;amp;Bones, and how we use writing and storytelling to bring about positive social change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wind&amp;Bones in Korea!</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/in-korea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/in-korea/</guid>
      <description>How can stories, books, museums, and other parts of our shared culture bring about social change? We think about these things a lot, so it&amp;rsquo;s been a delight to be visiting the seaside city of Busan in Korea, where we were at the World Humanities Forum, talking about Humanities in Relationship: Towards Communication, Coexistence and Empathy.&#xA;Wind&amp;amp;Bones&amp;rsquo;s Dr Will Buckingham was presenting a paper at the forum on how the idea of philoxenia — a term coming from Greek meaning &amp;ldquo;friendship with that which is other&amp;rdquo; — can help us think through the significance of museums for their visitors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Equality, Diversity and Inclusion</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/equalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/equalities/</guid>
      <description>Wind&amp;amp;Bones Equality, Diversity and Inclusion Policies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safeguarding</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/safeguarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/safeguarding/</guid>
      <description>Wind&amp;amp;Bones Equality, Safeguarding Policies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Storytelling in the Liberal Arts and Sciences</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/las-osun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/las-osun/</guid>
      <description>Seven years ago we ran our first storytelling workshop as Wind&amp;amp;Bones. This first ever workshop was a multilingual event with asylum-seekers and refugees in Leicester, UK. It was a sheer, boisterous delight, held in a community hall in the centre of the city. We shared and wrote stories in multiple languages, whilst at the same time an exercise class was taking part in another corner of the hall, and lunch being served in yet another.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Term for Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/new-term-myanmar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/new-term-myanmar/</guid>
      <description>If you have been following our work for a while, you will know that at Wind&amp;amp;Bones, we have long-standing connections with Myanmar. In 2017, Wind&amp;amp;Bones&amp;rsquo;s Will Buckingham was on the founding faculty at the Parami Institute, which is now Parami University. Then between 2018 and 2019, Will was back in Myanmar to work on a writing residency with his Wind&amp;amp;Bones collaborator and co-director, Hannah Stevens, delivering workshops on writing, ethics and social change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hot Chocolate - False Perceptions, True Stories</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/hot-chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/hot-chocolate/</guid>
      <description>This July 2023, we worked in Dundee, Scotland with a group of young people, exploring the art of manifesto-writing, and asking how telling truer, better stories can help to counter false perceptions of young people and their lives.&#xA;We explored manifestos from the last one hundred and fifty years, and then collectively wrote a manifesto of our own, one that aimed to get to the heart of the complex, multi-faceted experience of what it means to be a young person today.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waterford Food Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/waterford-food-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 12:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/waterford-food-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>Last summer, we worked with GIY (Ireland), Ashoka, and the wonderful Dr. Sarah Prosser on a project to develop a manifesto for future food in the Waterford Bioregion. We co-ran a workshop with local farmers, community members and consumers, leading to the drafting of a manifesto for rethinking the centrality of food in all of our lives.&#xA;You can read more about the project here: Waterford Manifesto.&#xA;We&amp;rsquo;re delighted that the manifesto is now available on YouTube, read by Ray McGrath, who took part in the workshop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wind&amp;Bones in Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/wind-and-bones-taiwan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/wind-and-bones-taiwan/</guid>
      <description>This August, we&amp;rsquo;ll be packing our bags, and heading over to Taiwan. We were last in Taiwan four years ago, on a short visit from Myanmar, and we found ourselves smitten. In particular, while in Tainan (our favourite Taiwanese city), we visited the National Museum of Taiwan Literature, and we were enormously impressed by the nuanced and thoughtful take on the ways in which literature can act as a driver of positive social change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Their Absence, Now in Bulgarian</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/in-their-absence-bulgarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/in-their-absence-bulgarian/</guid>
      <description>Wind&amp;amp;Bones were based in Bulgaria for over two years, and so we are particularly delighted to see Hannah Stevens&amp;rsquo;s brilliant short story collection, In Their Absence being released in a Bulgarian language edition, translated by Ana Pipeva.&#xA;The translation, Когато ги няма (Kogato gi nyama), is published by Altera, and has already attracted significant media attention.&#xA;If you speak Bulgarian, have a listen in here on Bulgarian National Radio. And if you want to buy the book, this is the link</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dragon-Carving Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/dragon-carving-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/dragon-carving-updates/</guid>
      <description>Our Dragon-Carving for Writers Project is well underway. In this project, we are exploring the contemporary uses of Liu Xie&amp;rsquo;s medieval Chinese classic, the Wenxin diaolong (文心雕龍), or The Literary Mind and the Carving of Dragons.&#xA;Last month, we held our workshop with our brilliant writers — Dr Sipei Lu 陆思培, Ningli Deng 邓宁立, Zhenhao Shi 史镇豪, Dr Hannah Stevens, Yuhang Zhang 张煜航, and Will Buckingham. We talked about three chapters from Liu&amp;rsquo;s book, exploring the text&amp;rsquo;s philosophical underpinnings, insights into the craft of writing, and discussion of the writer&amp;rsquo;s life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dragon-carving for Writers</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/dragon-carving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/dragon-carving/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2023 Project location: Scotland / China Project partners: Dr Sipei Lu, British Council Overview In 2023, we were awarded a Connections Through Culture grant for a pilot project working on cross-cultural creativity. Working with China-based academic and writer Dr Sipei Lu, we are running a workshop for Chinese and English writers, exploring Liu Xie&amp;rsquo;s medieval Chinese classic the Wenxin diaolong (文心雕龍), or The Heart of Literature, the Carving of Dragons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Dr Tim Hannigan</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/credne-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/credne-interview/</guid>
      <description>Two years ago, we recorded this interview with the brilliant travel writer, Dr Tim Hannigan. At the time, Tim was working on the Credne project at Dublin City University, exploring the nature of creativity.&#xA;Tim was a great interviewer: friendly, enthusiastic and astute, and as a result, the interview gives a really good overview of our work at Wind&amp;amp;Bones. The interview below is very lightly edited. Happy reading!&#xA;On creativity Tim Hello, Will and Hannah.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Enduring Questions with the Premise Institute</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/premise-institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/premise-institute/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2023 Project location: UK / USA Project partners: Premise Institute Overview In the spring of 2023, we&amp;rsquo;re partnering with the Premise Institute, based over in the promised land of literature that is Portland, Oregon. Premise is a community &amp;ldquo;where the curious come to connect, learn, and grapple with life’s enduring questions.&amp;rdquo; Premise is neither a book club nor a college-style course. Instead, it is a chance to explore wide-ranging questions about human life, based on the shared experience of reading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wind&amp;Bones - Looking forward, Looking Back</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/looking-forward-looking-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/looking-forward-looking-back/</guid>
      <description>Happy New Year from Madeira, where we are taking a working break for a couple of weeks. While here in Funchal, we&amp;rsquo;re looking over what we have done in 2022 and making plans for 2023.&#xA;2022 in Review Wind&amp;amp;Bones move to Scotland Last year was incredibly busy. The most significant change was that we moved from Sofia, Bulgaria, to Dundee, Scotland. After almost 2½ years working in Bulgaria, we felt like we needed to reconnect to our UK roots, so we moved up to Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After the Coup - Storytelling and Education</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/myanmar-teachers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/myanmar-teachers/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Autumn 2022 Project location: Myanmar / Thailand Overview In the autumn of 2022, we worked with a Myanmar-based NGO and a group of community teachers on a project to develop storytelling skills in the classroom.&#xA;The teachers with whom we worked are continuing to provide education in the difficult post-coup landscape of Myanmar. We ran this project with a Myanmar-based NGO to explore how storytelling can be used as a pedagogical tool.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chance Encounters</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/chance-encounters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/chance-encounters/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Summer 2022 Project location: Wigtown, Scotland Project partners: Wigtown Book Festival Overview In 2023, we were invited to the Wigtown book festival to run a public drop-in writing workshops called Chance Encounters. We invited members of the public to share stories about their own chance encounters, each story determined by a roll of the dice.&#xA;Then put their stories in unmarked envelopes.&#xA;When more passers-by came to share their stories, we gave them a story from one of the sealed envelopes to take away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waterford Harvest Festival Story Farm</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/story-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/story-farm/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Summer 2022 Project location: Waterford, Ireland Project partners: GIY (Ireland) Overview In the summer of 2022, we were invited to Waterford, Ireland to take part in the Waterford Harvest Festival, run by the social enterprise Grow It Yourself (GIY).&#xA;The festival was a festival of food done right. And we were farming stories about food, community, culture and place.&#xA;Project Outcomes Over the course of the weekend, we gathered a huge pile of stories to share with the public, and with GIY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Food Done Right, in Waterford, Ireland</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/food-done-right-in-waterford-ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/food-done-right-in-waterford-ireland/</guid>
      <description>The Waterford Harvest Festival kicks off this September in Waterford, Ireland. Run by the brilliant social enterprise GIY, the festival is a three-day celebration of “food done right”, an exploration of food, heritage, and sustainability.&#xA;At Wind&amp;amp;Bones, we&amp;rsquo;re immensely excited to have been invited to be writers in residence at the festival. So on the 10th and 11th of September, we&amp;rsquo;ll be over in Ireland, setting up a story farm. We&amp;rsquo;ll be inviting members of the public to plant the seeds of new stories, and to watch them grow in new and surprising directions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dandelion Festival</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/dandelion-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/dandelion-festival/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Summer 2022 Project location: Glasgow, Scotland Project partners: Unboxed UK, Dandelion Festival. Overview In the summer of 2020, we worked with the Dandelion Festival to delivery three days of workshops with the general public in Kelvingrove Park, Glasgow.&#xA;Dandelion was a festival dedicated to rethinking our relationships with food and growing. We set up in a potting shed in the park, where we spent three intensive days working with members of the public.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Countering Harmful Stories With Better Stories</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/countering-harmful-stories-with-better-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/countering-harmful-stories-with-better-stories/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we were at the British Ambassador&amp;rsquo;s Residence in Sofia for a fundraising event with the Emprove Foundation for our Awakening Between the Lines Project. Here&amp;rsquo;s the speech we wrote for the event.&#xA;Good evening. I&amp;rsquo;m Will Buckingham, co-director of Wind&amp;amp;Bones, and over there is my colleague and Wind&amp;amp;Bones co-director Hannah Stevens. Wind&amp;amp;Bones is a social enterprise now based in Scotland, and we run projects at the intersection of writing, creativity and social change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Awakening Between the Lines</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/awakening-between-the-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/awakening-between-the-lines/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2022-2023 Project location: Sofia, Bulgaria Project partners: British Embassy, Bulgaria; the Emprove Foundation, Bulgaria. Overview We worked with the Emprove Foundation and British Embassy, Bulgaria, on an innovative project to raise awareness of the issue of domestic abuse. Emprove Foundation work with women survivors of abuse. For this project, we ran a six-week intensive workshop on writing for a group of women survivors.&#xA;The stories were edited into final form and cross-translated between Bulgarian and English.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At the National Gallery, Sofia</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/awakening/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/awakening/</guid>
      <description>Next Monday, we&amp;rsquo;re back in Bulgaria to see the exhibition from our project with the Emprove Foundation, working with survivors of domestic abuse on telling and sharing micro-stories. We intensively workshopped a series of stories with a group of fifteen talented women survivors, and artists have been commissioned to produce artworks inspired by the stories. These artworks are the subject of an exhibition that is currently running in The National Gallery of Bulgaria Kvadrat 500.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stories Galore At the Dandelion Festival</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/dandelion-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/dandelion-weekend/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, we spent three days in an unexpectedly sunny Glasgow at the Dandelion Festival, a part of the UK-wide Unboxed Festival.&#xA;Dandelion is about deepening our relationship with the natural world, about the joy of growing, and about thinking more deeply about where our food comes from.&#xA;So over the course of the weekend, we were in a potting shed — a little wooden hut — asking people to share their own stories about food: the food they love, the food they hate, the food they like to cook, the food that has caused them to fall in and out of love, the food that reminds them of home.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wind&amp;Bones CIC are now Scottish</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/scotland/</guid>
      <description>Today, we&amp;rsquo;ve been celebrating the fact that Wind&amp;amp;Bones is now a thoroughly Scottish social enterprise. As we are here in Dundee for the long term, we decided to move our business from England to Scotland. This is easier said than done, as companies cannot be straightforwardly moved over the border. But with the help of the brilliant people at Senscot Legal, we&amp;rsquo;ve managed to work round the problem.&#xA;We&amp;rsquo;ve changed the name of our old CIC to Wind&amp;amp;Bones (England), and we&amp;rsquo;ve set up a new CIC called simply Wind&amp;amp;Bones, registered in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wind&amp;Bones are now based in Dundee!</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/dundee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/dundee/</guid>
      <description>Over the last couple of weeks, we&amp;rsquo;ve been busy moving our headquarters of operations from Sofia in Bulgaria to Dundee in Scotland. We landed here a week ago, and since then, we&amp;rsquo;ve been busy unpacking boxes and getting settled. It&amp;rsquo;s great to be up in Scotland. We&amp;rsquo;ve only been here a few days. But already, Dundee has been hugely welcoming. It has been great to start making connections and getting to know the local writing scene.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto for a Regenerative Bioregion, Waterford</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/waterford-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/waterford-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Summer 2022 Project location: Waterford, Ireland Project partners: GIY (Ireland), Dr Sarah Prosser Overview The Bioregional Weaving Labs Collective is an ambitious project of the Ashoka foundation that aims to reweave connections between peoples, communities, cultures and the natural world. Waterford, Ireland, is one of the bioregions that is spearheading this exciting initiative.&#xA;Wind&amp;amp;Bones were invited to co-lead a workshop with Waterford&amp;rsquo;s own &amp;ldquo;weaver&amp;rdquo;, Dr. Sarah Prosser. We worked with local farmers, community members and consumers to write a manifesto for rethinking the centrality of food in our lives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Stories that Make Us - Working With Women Survivors</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/the-stories-that-make-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/the-stories-that-make-us/</guid>
      <description>This November, we&amp;rsquo;re starting a new project with the brilliant Bulgarian Emprove Foundation, who work with women survivors of domestic abuse.&#xA;The project is called The Stories that Make Us: Creative writing with women survivors — finding new models for creative intervention. Over six weeks between November and December this year, we&amp;rsquo;ll be working with a group of women survivors, exploring how storytelling can be used to build community and bring about both individual and social transformation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Education in Post-Coup Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/education-myanmar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/education-myanmar/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a few new projects recently, including a collaboration with Parami University in Myanmar. We were writers in residence at Parami back in 2018-2019, and after the military coup of February 1st this year, we&amp;rsquo;ve been deeply preoccupied with the unfolding situation over there. So we&amp;rsquo;re delighted to be working with Parami University again, running some remote courses via Zoom for students across Myanmar.&#xA;We&amp;rsquo;re running three courses in all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking for Wisdom - A New Collaboration for Wind&amp;Bones</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/looking-for-wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/looking-for-wisdom/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re delighted that Looking for Wisdom, the philosophy-by-email project run by Dr Will Buckingham, is now a part of Wind&amp;amp;Bones. At Wind&amp;amp;Bones, we believe that creative writing and creative thinking have the power to change the world. So this new collaboration is a great fit for what we do.&#xA;Looking for Wisdom brings the world&amp;rsquo;s philosophy to your inbox with free weekly Philosopher Files. The project was launched formally on January 1st this year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Wind&amp;Bones?</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/why-wind-and-bones/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/why-wind-and-bones/</guid>
      <description>When we set up Wind&amp;amp;Bones back in 2018, we wanted a name that reflected our vision of writing, creativity and social change. And after a lot of discussion, eventually we came up with Wind&amp;amp;Bones.&#xA;But what&amp;rsquo;s in a name? And why are we called this? Is one of us &amp;ldquo;Wind&amp;rdquo; and one of us &amp;ldquo;Bones&amp;rdquo;? Are these our secret superhero names? Alas, no! But the real story is fun and interesting too, and it goes back to medieval China.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Hello, Stranger&#39; hits the shops this July</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/hello-stranger/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 15:28:43 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/hello-stranger/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re delighted that our very own Will Buckingham&amp;rsquo;s Hello, Stranger: How We Find Connection in a Disconnected World is coming out from Granta this July 1st.&#xA;Will&amp;rsquo;s book brings together insights from philosophy, anthropology, history, and literature to explore how our traditions of meeting with strangers can mitigate the issues of our time. Taking in stories of loneliness, exile, and friendship from classical times to the modern day, and alighting in adapting communities from Birmingham to Myanmar, Hello, Stranger asks: how do we set aside our instinctive xenophobia – fear of outsiders – and embrace our equally natural philoxenia – love of strangers and newness?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creativity on the Margins of Academia</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/creativity-margins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/creativity-margins/</guid>
      <description>The other week, we had the pleasure of sitting down for a long Zoom chat about creativity with scholar, travel-writer and researcher Dr Tim Hannigan. Tim works for Dublin City University on their DCU CREDNE — Forging Creativity project.&#xA;We were talking about the connections between creativity and interdisciplinarity, why we want university creative writing to decamp from English departments to the art school, and the creative benefits of operating at the margins of formal academia.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing, Pleasure &amp; the Myth of the Suffering Artist</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/writing-and-pleasure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/writing-and-pleasure/</guid>
      <description>At Wind&amp;amp;Bones, one myth we’re keen to dispel is the myth of the suffering artist. One of the things we do when working with writers is help them find ways to seek out delight and pleasure in their writing. Because once you have pleasure and delight, you have energy and life, and when you have energy and life, you are already half-way to creating something worthwhile.&#xA;Of course, writing can be difficult (tell us about it).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspirations - Maisie Chan</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/inspirations-maisie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/inspirations-maisie/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we’re featuring the fabulous Maisie Chan. Read our wide-ranging interview about writing, representation, the ongoing harms of orientalism, and the dedication it takes to be a damn good storyteller.&#xA;Hello, Maisie. It’s great to talk to you. We’re particularly excited because you are the first writer in our Inspirations series, where we feature writers committed to using their words to make the world a better place. This is a really exciting time to be talking to you because you’ve got not one, but two books coming out in the coming few months: Danny Chung Does Not Do Maths (Piccadilly Press), published in the USA as Danny Chung Sums it Up (Amulet Books), and Tiger Warrior: Attack of the Dragon King (Orchard Books).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 10:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Privacy and legal info for Wind&amp;amp;Bones.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Universe of Stories</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/goethe-institut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/goethe-institut/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: June 2020 Project location: Sofia, Bulgaria Project partners: Goethe Institut, Bulgaria; Caritas, Bulgaria Overview For World Refugee Day in 2020, we ran a day of writing workshops in collaboration with the Goethe Institut, Bulgaria, and Caritas.&#xA;During the workshop, participants shared stories in multiple languages: English, Bulgarian, Kurdish and Arabic. We were aided by Sophia, Caritas&amp;rsquo;s brilliant translator.&#xA;Project Outcomes What we loved about the stories the participants told was how varied they were, how in a few brief hours we mapped out the vastness of human experience: we had funny stories and sad stories, everyday stories and stories about extraordinary events.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenpeace Writers&#39; &amp; Activists&#39; Cafe</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/writers-activists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/writers-activists/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2020 Project location: Sofia, Bulgaria Project partners: Greenpeace, Bulgaria. Overview In 2020, we set up a Writers&amp;rsquo; and Activists&amp;rsquo; café with Greenpeace, Bulgaria. The idea of the café was that we would gather every week in Greenpeace&amp;rsquo;s wonderful community space in the heart of Sofia, and we would explore how writing can be used to bring about positive social change.&#xA;The café was free to access, run on a donation-only basis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethical Leadership with Mote Oo</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/mote-oo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/mote-oo/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2018-2023 Project location: Myanmar Project partners: Mote Oo Education, Myanmar; Payap University, Thailand Overview In 2018, we were commissioned by Mote Oo to write a coursebook on ethical leadership that was sensitive to the needs of community groups, civil society organisations and NGOs in Myanmar.&#xA;We looked around at the material available on ethical leadership, and found it wanting. There were several problems with pre-existing courses:&#xA;They were overly business-focussed, written primarily for the corporate world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Bridges with Paung Ku</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/bulding-bridges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/bulding-bridges/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2019 Project location: Yangon, Myanmar Project partners: Paung Ku, Myanmar. Overview In 2019, we ran a three-day workshop with staff from the Myanmar civil society organisation, Paung Ku, who are an organisation committed to driving positive social change. Paung Khu&amp;rsquo;s vision is of a pluralistic society that values the diversity of ethnicity, culture and belief in Myanmar, and that ensures equity and respect for the rights of all, particularly those who are marginalised.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EmpathEAST talk</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/empatheast-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/empatheast-talk/</guid>
      <description>We were invited to EmpathEAST in Plovdiv in 2019 to talk about our work at Wind&amp;amp;Bones. So we gave a talk, telling the story of Wind&amp;amp;Bones up to that point.&#xA;Intro [Hannah] Hello!&#xA;We’re delighted to be here at EmpathEAST 2019, and excited to be working together over the next few days.&#xA;It’s also great to be in the lovely city of Plovdiv and to be getting a sense of the history, the cultural richness and the energy of 2019’s European Capital of Culture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creative Writing at Volvi</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/volvi-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/volvi-writing/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2019 Project location: Volvi, Greece Project partners: Refugee Trauma Initiative Overview We were invited by the brilliantly innovative NGO, Refugee Trauma Initiative, to run creative writing workshops in Volvi refugee camp, north of Thessaloniki, Greece.&#xA;We worked with a wide variety of young people, telling and sharing stories in multiple languages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto - A workshop and talk</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/manifestos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/manifestos/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2019 Project location: Plovdiv, Bulgaria Project partners: Ideas Factory, Bulgaria Overview We were invited to the 2019 EmpathEAST forum for Empathy-driven Social Change in Plovdiv, Bulgaria to talk about our Wind&amp;amp;Bones work.&#xA;The three-day forum was a gathering of social activists, changemakers, artists and academics, all interested in exploring the ways in which it might be possible to bring about positive social change.&#xA;We gave a talk to the delegates (see the link below) and ran our first ever manifesto-writing workshop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writers in Residence at The Parami Institute</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/parami-residency/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/parami-residency/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2018-2019 Project location: Yangon, Myanmar Project partners: The Parami Institute, Myanmar Overview Between 2018 and 2019, we were writers in residence at the Parami Institute in Yangon, Myanmar. We ran a series of public-facing writing workshops, with a focus on writing for social change.&#xA;We worked with a diverse group of students: NGO workers, doctors, former political prisoners, community radio hosts, journalists, writers, activists and many more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Write Here - Writing for Refugees</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/write-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/projects/write-here/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Summer 2017 Project location: Leicester, England Project partners: Writing East Midlands, Leicester City of Sanctuary Overview This was our very first project: a series of workshops with refugee writers in the city of Leicester. We decided when we set up the workshops that we wanted them to be about writing and storytelling, rather than English-language classes. So we made the decision that we would encourage writers to write in whatever language they felt comfortable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Writing and storytelling for social change Wind&amp;amp;Bones is an innovative social enterprise dedicated to exploring the transformative power of writing and storytelling. Run by British writers Dr Hannah Stevens &amp;amp; Dr Will Buckingham, we are registered in Dundee, Scotland, and we work across the globe.&#xA;We work with organisations and individuals on projects that bring together writing, creativity and social change.&#xA;We take our name from the Medieval Chinese writer, Liu Xie, and his book the Wenxin diaolong (文心雕龍), or The Heart of Literature, the Carving of Dragons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Almost there!</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/almost-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/almost-there/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for signing up! You are almost there. All you need to do now is check your email, and click the confirmation link. Then you&amp;rsquo;re good to go.&#xA;Can&amp;rsquo;t find the email? Check your spam box! If you mark Looking for Wisdom emails as non-spam, that will help them be delivered to the right place!&#xA;Return to the home page</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Do you have a question about the site? Do you want to cook up some fun projects with us? Or do you just want to say hello?&#xA;Get in touch with Wind&amp;amp;Bones, and we&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you as soon as we can.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elements</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/elements/</guid>
      <description>A paragraph looks like this — Globally incubate standards compliant channels before scalable benefits. Quickly disseminate superior deliverables whereas web-enabled applications. Quickly drive clicks-and-mortar catalysts for change before vertical architectures. Credibly reintermediate backend ideas for cross-platform models. Continually reintermediate integrated processes through technically sound intellectual capital. Holistically foster superior methodologies.&#xA;Headings by default: H1 Default styles for headings H2 Default styles for headings H3 Default styles for headings H4 Default styles for headings H5 Default styles for headings H6 Default styles for headings Lists Ordered list example: Poutine drinking vinegar bitters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring with Wind&amp;Bones</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/mentor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/mentor/</guid>
      <description>Get help with your writing Are you an academic wanting to write for a broader audience? A novelist working on your first book? A nonfiction writer unsure where to go next? At Wind&amp;amp;Bones, we offer mentoring for a diversity of writers, from absolute beginners to those with years of experience.&#xA;How it works We offer bespoke mentoring. Our services include:&#xA;Reading and giving comprehensive feedback on your work Line-by-line editing Meeting online or face to face If you are interseted in mentoring, the first stage is to get in touch to talk about what you are working on, and what help you need.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Success!</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/success/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/success/</guid>
      <description>Your message has been sent successfully!&#xA;We&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you as soon as we can, usually within 48 hours.&#xA;Return to the home page</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thanks</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/thanks/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for signing up to Looking for Wisdom&amp;rsquo;s email newsletter! It&amp;rsquo;s really good to have you on board.&#xA;Remember that we also have a small Facebook community where you can chat to fellow subscribers.&#xA;Return to the home page</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
