<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wansha Philosophy Salon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/wansha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/wansha/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2024 Project location: Tainan, Taiwan Project partners: Wansha Performing Arts Centre / 涴莎藝術展演中心 Overview From January 2024 to November 2024, we&amp;rsquo;re running a public philosophy salon at the Wansha Performing Arts Centre in Tainan. The salon meets on the third Saturday of every month, to ask how philosophy can throw light on the puzzles and paradoxes of everyday life.&#xA;The salon is run entirely in Mandarin (which is a fun challenge for us), and is free for the public to attend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Down the Generations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/down-the-generations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 01:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/down-the-generations/</guid>
      <description>It was my father who taught me to cook. In my family he prepared meals for all of us — breakfast, lunch and dinner. This is very different from a traditional Asian family.&#xA;The reason my father started to cook was because he wanted to reproduce the dishes made by his father, our grandpa. My father&amp;rsquo;s father passed away in my father&amp;rsquo;s early childhood. I never knew him.&#xA;Since learning why my father cooked, I have asked him to teach me some basic cooking skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In a Foreign Land</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/foreign-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/foreign-land/</guid>
      <description>After arriving in Tokyo a year ago, my cooking skills have noticeably improved. Since being here I&amp;rsquo;ve grown accustomed to the high prices of fruits and gradually accepted the limited variety of vegetables. These new restraints have meant I’ve grown in creativity in the kitchen.&#xA;The excellent quality of beef here is impressive though finding a whole beef shank can be quite difficult. Even when cooking for family, Japanese people seldom buy such large cuts of meat in one go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwanese Kimchi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/taiwanese-kimchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/taiwanese-kimchi/</guid>
      <description>My grandmother once told me that in her childhood she thought that Taiwanese kimchi was the most delicious food. When I was a child, she told me a bedside story about her early life. She told me how, in the early days of Taiwan, families with farming backgrounds faced financial struggles. They relied on thin porridge with a few small, pickled dried fish, or soy sauce. They rarely had the opportunity to enjoy dishes with meat or vegetables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>我媽媽的越南菜 | My Mother&#39;s Vietnamese Food</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vietnamese-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 05:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vietnamese-food/</guid>
      <description>我媽媽的越南菜 我的母親來自越南， 所以 當我吃到河粉、法國麵包（越南）、越南春捲時，我就會想起媽媽， 我甚至會去比較， 誰做得比較好吃。&#xA;不過並不是拿我媽做參考，我媽沒有做過河粉給我吃過。或是說：我沒有印象，可能有。反倒是她常做春捲、雞肉稀飯、生菜沙拉。 這三樣沒人能贏過她。&#xA;***— 張芳瑋 ***&#xA;My Mother&amp;rsquo;s Vietnamese Food My mother is from Vietnam, so when I eat phở, bánh mì, or Vietnamese spring rolls, I think of my mum. I even compare who makes them the best. But I don&amp;rsquo;t use my mum as a reference, because my mother has never made me phở to eat. Or, to put it another way, I don&amp;rsquo;t have any recollection of it, but perhaps she did.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Complicated Relationship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/complicated-relationship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/complicated-relationship/</guid>
      <description>I have a complicated relationship with chai. Kenyan chai, not the Indian version. The milk is warmed first, before the water, the tea-dust — fragrant Kenyan tea from the Rift Valley highlands —, and the sugar are all added. It is all done by eye. I have never met a family who follows a recipe.&#xA;Chai is what we serve to guests. It is the first thing we have in the morning, and probably the last thing we have before sleeping.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blue Eyes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blue-eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blue-eyes/</guid>
      <description>When the waitress began to speak, I looked closely at her face, and I noticed that she had the most unusual eyes.&#xA;I think she wore contact lenses because her eyes were blue, but not a crystal-like, light blue like I usually see at home: they were deep navy, almost purple. And I&amp;rsquo;d never seen eyes like that before.&#xA;— Hannah Stevens</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cat Cake</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cat-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 05:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cat-cake/</guid>
      <description>We were walking home late one evening when I saw it. It was a white sign with black writing that read &amp;lsquo;Cake&amp;rsquo; in English.&#xA;There was the image of a cat on the sign and the cat wore sunglasses. As we got closer I could smell the cake. It smelled of cooked sugar, beaten eggs, creamed butter.&#xA;We didn&amp;rsquo;t stop there that night but I want to go back.&#xA;— Hannah Stevens</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culinary Heaven</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/culinary-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 05:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/culinary-heaven/</guid>
      <description>Tainan is a culinary heaven. It flourishes with lively, historic flavours. Every dish echoes the city&amp;rsquo;s rich heritage. Food in Tainan is a vibrant fusion of tradition and innovation on the taste buds.&#xA;Waking up in the morning, have a bowl of hot beef soup from the market, or a soul-soothing bowl of tender minced pork, to make you feel energetic.&#xA;After work in the morning, have a milkfish feast, especially the belly and skin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Equality, Diversity and Inclusion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/equalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/equalities/</guid>
      <description>Wind&amp;amp;Bones Equality, Diversity and Inclusion Policies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safeguarding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/safeguarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/safeguarding/</guid>
      <description>Wind&amp;amp;Bones Equality, Safeguarding Policies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dragon-carving for Writers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/dragon-carving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/dragon-carving/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2023 Project location: Scotland / China Project partners: Dr Sipei Lu, British Council Overview In 2023, we were awarded a Connections Through Culture grant for a pilot project working on cross-cultural creativity. Working with China-based academic and writer Dr Sipei Lu, we are running a workshop for Chinese and English writers, exploring Liu Xie&amp;rsquo;s medieval Chinese classic the Wenxin diaolong (文心雕龍), or The Heart of Literature, the Carving of Dragons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Enduring Questions with the Premise Institute</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/premise-institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/premise-institute/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2023 Project location: UK / USA Project partners: Premise Institute Overview In the spring of 2023, we&amp;rsquo;re partnering with the Premise Institute, based over in the promised land of literature that is Portland, Oregon. Premise is a community &amp;ldquo;where the curious come to connect, learn, and grapple with life’s enduring questions.&amp;rdquo; Premise is neither a book club nor a college-style course. Instead, it is a chance to explore wide-ranging questions about human life, based on the shared experience of reading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After the Coup - Storytelling and Education</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/myanmar-teachers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/myanmar-teachers/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Autumn 2022 Project location: Myanmar / Thailand Overview In the autumn of 2022, we worked with a Myanmar-based NGO and a group of community teachers on a project to develop storytelling skills in the classroom.&#xA;The teachers with whom we worked are continuing to provide education in the difficult post-coup landscape of Myanmar. We ran this project with a Myanmar-based NGO to explore how storytelling can be used as a pedagogical tool.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chance Encounters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/chance-encounters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/chance-encounters/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Summer 2022 Project location: Wigtown, Scotland Project partners: Wigtown Book Festival Overview In 2023, we were invited to the Wigtown book festival to run a public drop-in writing workshops called Chance Encounters. We invited members of the public to share stories about their own chance encounters, each story determined by a roll of the dice.&#xA;Then put their stories in unmarked envelopes.&#xA;When more passers-by came to share their stories, we gave them a story from one of the sealed envelopes to take away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waterford Harvest Festival Story Farm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/story-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/story-farm/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Summer 2022 Project location: Waterford, Ireland Project partners: GIY (Ireland) Overview In the summer of 2022, we were invited to Waterford, Ireland to take part in the Waterford Harvest Festival, run by the social enterprise Grow It Yourself (GIY).&#xA;The festival was a festival of food done right. And we were farming stories about food, community, culture and place.&#xA;Project Outcomes Over the course of the weekend, we gathered a huge pile of stories to share with the public, and with GIY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dandelion Festival</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/dandelion-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/dandelion-festival/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Summer 2022 Project location: Glasgow, Scotland Project partners: Unboxed UK, Dandelion Festival. Overview In the summer of 2020, we worked with the Dandelion Festival to delivery three days of workshops with the general public in Kelvingrove Park, Glasgow.&#xA;Dandelion was a festival dedicated to rethinking our relationships with food and growing. We set up in a potting shed in the park, where we spent three intensive days working with members of the public.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Awakening Between the Lines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/awakening-between-the-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/awakening-between-the-lines/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2022-2023 Project location: Sofia, Bulgaria Project partners: British Embassy, Bulgaria; the Emprove Foundation, Bulgaria. Overview We worked with the Emprove Foundation and British Embassy, Bulgaria, on an innovative project to raise awareness of the issue of domestic abuse. Emprove Foundation work with women survivors of abuse. For this project, we ran a six-week intensive workshop on writing for a group of women survivors.&#xA;The stories were edited into final form and cross-translated between Bulgarian and English.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto for a Regenerative Bioregion, Waterford</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/waterford-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/waterford-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Summer 2022 Project location: Waterford, Ireland Project partners: GIY (Ireland), Dr Sarah Prosser Overview The Bioregional Weaving Labs Collective is an ambitious project of the Ashoka foundation that aims to reweave connections between peoples, communities, cultures and the natural world. Waterford, Ireland, is one of the bioregions that is spearheading this exciting initiative.&#xA;Wind&amp;amp;Bones were invited to co-lead a workshop with Waterford&amp;rsquo;s own &amp;ldquo;weaver&amp;rdquo;, Dr. Sarah Prosser. We worked with local farmers, community members and consumers to write a manifesto for rethinking the centrality of food in our lives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 10:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Privacy and legal info for Wind&amp;amp;Bones.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Universe of Stories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/goethe-institut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/goethe-institut/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: June 2020 Project location: Sofia, Bulgaria Project partners: Goethe Institut, Bulgaria; Caritas, Bulgaria Overview For World Refugee Day in 2020, we ran a day of writing workshops in collaboration with the Goethe Institut, Bulgaria, and Caritas.&#xA;During the workshop, participants shared stories in multiple languages: English, Bulgarian, Kurdish and Arabic. We were aided by Sophia, Caritas&amp;rsquo;s brilliant translator.&#xA;Project Outcomes What we loved about the stories the participants told was how varied they were, how in a few brief hours we mapped out the vastness of human experience: we had funny stories and sad stories, everyday stories and stories about extraordinary events.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenpeace Writers&#39; &amp; Activists&#39; Cafe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/writers-activists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/writers-activists/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2020 Project location: Sofia, Bulgaria Project partners: Greenpeace, Bulgaria. Overview In 2020, we set up a Writers&amp;rsquo; and Activists&amp;rsquo; café with Greenpeace, Bulgaria. The idea of the café was that we would gather every week in Greenpeace&amp;rsquo;s wonderful community space in the heart of Sofia, and we would explore how writing can be used to bring about positive social change.&#xA;The café was free to access, run on a donation-only basis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethical Leadership with Mote Oo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/mote-oo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/mote-oo/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2018-2023 Project location: Myanmar Project partners: Mote Oo Education, Myanmar; Payap University, Thailand Overview In 2018, we were commissioned by Mote Oo to write a coursebook on ethical leadership that was sensitive to the needs of community groups, civil society organisations and NGOs in Myanmar.&#xA;We looked around at the material available on ethical leadership, and found it wanting. There were several problems with pre-existing courses:&#xA;They were overly business-focussed, written primarily for the corporate world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Bridges with Paung Ku</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/bulding-bridges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/bulding-bridges/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2019 Project location: Yangon, Myanmar Project partners: Paung Ku, Myanmar. Overview In 2019, we ran a three-day workshop with staff from the Myanmar civil society organisation, Paung Ku, who are an organisation committed to driving positive social change. Paung Khu&amp;rsquo;s vision is of a pluralistic society that values the diversity of ethnicity, culture and belief in Myanmar, and that ensures equity and respect for the rights of all, particularly those who are marginalised.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creative Writing at Volvi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/volvi-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/volvi-writing/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2019 Project location: Volvi, Greece Project partners: Refugee Trauma Initiative Overview We were invited by the brilliantly innovative NGO, Refugee Trauma Initiative, to run creative writing workshops in Volvi refugee camp, north of Thessaloniki, Greece.&#xA;We worked with a wide variety of young people, telling and sharing stories in multiple languages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto - A workshop and talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/manifestos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/manifestos/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2019 Project location: Plovdiv, Bulgaria Project partners: Ideas Factory, Bulgaria Overview We were invited to the 2019 EmpathEAST forum for Empathy-driven Social Change in Plovdiv, Bulgaria to talk about our Wind&amp;amp;Bones work.&#xA;The three-day forum was a gathering of social activists, changemakers, artists and academics, all interested in exploring the ways in which it might be possible to bring about positive social change.&#xA;We gave a talk to the delegates (see the link below) and ran our first ever manifesto-writing workshop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writers in Residence at The Parami Institute</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/parami-residency/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/parami-residency/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: 2018-2019 Project location: Yangon, Myanmar Project partners: The Parami Institute, Myanmar Overview Between 2018 and 2019, we were writers in residence at the Parami Institute in Yangon, Myanmar. We ran a series of public-facing writing workshops, with a focus on writing for social change.&#xA;We worked with a diverse group of students: NGO workers, doctors, former political prisoners, community radio hosts, journalists, writers, activists and many more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Write Here - Writing for Refugees</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/write-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 08:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/write-here/</guid>
      <description>Info Project date: Summer 2017 Project location: Leicester, England Project partners: Writing East Midlands, Leicester City of Sanctuary Overview This was our very first project: a series of workshops with refugee writers in the city of Leicester. We decided when we set up the workshops that we wanted them to be about writing and storytelling, rather than English-language classes. So we made the decision that we would encourage writers to write in whatever language they felt comfortable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Almost there!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/almost-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/almost-there/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for signing up! You are almost there. All you need to do now is check your email, and click the confirmation link. Then you&amp;rsquo;re good to go.&#xA;Can&amp;rsquo;t find the email? Check your spam box! If you mark Looking for Wisdom emails as non-spam, that will help them be delivered to the right place!&#xA;Return to the home page</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/elements/</guid>
      <description>A paragraph looks like this — Globally incubate standards compliant channels before scalable benefits. Quickly disseminate superior deliverables whereas web-enabled applications. Quickly drive clicks-and-mortar catalysts for change before vertical architectures. Credibly reintermediate backend ideas for cross-platform models. Continually reintermediate integrated processes through technically sound intellectual capital. Holistically foster superior methodologies.&#xA;Headings by default: H1 Default styles for headings H2 Default styles for headings H3 Default styles for headings H4 Default styles for headings H5 Default styles for headings H6 Default styles for headings Lists Ordered list example: Poutine drinking vinegar bitters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grandmother&#39;s dishes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-12-19-grandmother/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-12-19-grandmother/</guid>
      <description>I remember my grandmother as both affectionate and strict. She had a tough exterior but a soft heart, and she expressed her love in every action. She never said the words, &amp;ldquo;I love you,&amp;rdquo; but everything she did was an embodiment of love.&#xA;Her love manifested in numerous ways — holding hands while crossing the street, the small lamp guiding me home after evening classes, the late-night bowl of noodles when we were hungry, the shell-less shrimp she prepared, the adhesive bandage that appeared instantly when I got hurt, and the scolding when I was careless.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grandpa&#39;s Stewed Pork Rice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/grandpas-stewed-pork-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/grandpas-stewed-pork-rice/</guid>
      <description>The food I like most is made by my grandpa. He used to make stewed pork rice (滷肉飯), one of the most famous dishes on Taiwanese dining tables. Every time I got home, the smell always made me happy and joyful.&#xA;Now grandpa is a sick, so it is our turn to cook for him. Although we can&amp;rsquo;t make our stewed pork rice taste the same as grandpa&amp;rsquo;s, I still think it is delicious: it is one of the most delicious dishes of all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring with Wind&amp;Bones</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mentor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mentor/</guid>
      <description>Get help with your writing Are you an academic wanting to write for a broader audience? A novelist working on your first book? A nonfiction writer unsure where to go next? At Wind&amp;amp;Bones, we offer mentoring for a diversity of writers, from absolute beginners to those with years of experience.&#xA;How it works We offer bespoke mentoring. Our services include:&#xA;Reading and giving comprehensive feedback on your work Line-by-line editing Meeting online or face to face If you are interseted in mentoring, the first stage is to get in touch to talk about what you are working on, and what help you need.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Success!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/success/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/success/</guid>
      <description>Your message has been sent successfully!&#xA;We&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you as soon as we can, usually within 48 hours.&#xA;Return to the home page</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thanks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/thanks/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for signing up to Looking for Wisdom&amp;rsquo;s email newsletter! It&amp;rsquo;s really good to have you on board.&#xA;Remember that we also have a small Facebook community where you can chat to fellow subscribers.&#xA;Return to the home page</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>聯絡我們 | Contact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/contact/</guid>
      <description>我們想聽你們的故事！| We want to hear your stories! 食物 | 故事 | 日常生活的哲學 || Food | Stories | Daily-life philosophy 我們想聽聽你們的故事！&#xA;你吃過最美味的一餐是什麼？ 有什麼食物讓你想起家鄉？ 是誰教你做飯的？ 您是否因為美食而墜入愛河？ 使用任何語言填寫表格，分享您的故事。但我們提出一個挑戰，請保持簡短：不超過100字（中文150字符）。&#xA;我們將在網站上分享一些我們最喜愛的故事。&#xA;如果您想與我們聯絡，隨時使用此表格打聲招呼吧！&#xA;We want to hear your stories!&#xA;What is the best meal you have ever eaten? What food makes you think of home? Who taught you to cook? Have you ever fallen in love because of food? Fill in the form — in any language — and share your story.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>關於我們 ｜ About Us</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>滋養台南：食物 · 故事 · 哲學 食物滋養我們的身體。故事滋養我們的靈魂。哲學滋養我們的心靈。 您好，我們是Hannah Stevens博士和Will Buckingham博士，共同經營Wind&amp;amp;Bones CIC，一家致力於寫作和社會變革的社會企業。&#xA;在2023年12月，我們榮幸成為台南南寧文學·家的駐館作家。我們對食物、文化、故事和哲學之間的聯繫深感興趣。在駐地期間，我們將深入研究台南豐富的飲食文化。&#xA;在這個網站上，您可以查看我們駐地期間的最新消息。同時，您還可以閱讀其他人與我們分享的故事。如果您有自己的故事想要分享，請隨時透過聯絡表單 告訴我們。&#xA;或者，您也可以親自來南寧文學·家，與我們一同品味下午茶！&#xA;Nourishing Tainan with Wind&amp;amp;Bones: Food · Stories · Philosophy Food Nourishes Our Bodies. Stories nourish our spirit. Philosophy nourishes our mind. Hello, we are Dr. Hannah Stevens and Dr. Will Buckingham. Together, we direct Wind&amp;amp;Bones CIC, a social enterprise dedicated to writing and social change.&#xA;In December 2023, we are honored to be the Writers in Residence at Nanning Literature House in Tainan.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
