<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>creativity on Wind and Bones</title><link>https://www.windandbones.com/tags/creativity/</link><description>Recent content in creativity on Wind and Bones</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.windandbones.com/tags/creativity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Stories that Make Us: Giving a voice to women survivors</title><link>https://www.windandbones.com/blog/telling-our-stories/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.windandbones.com/blog/telling-our-stories/</guid><description>This November, we&amp;rsquo;re starting a new project with the brilliant Bulgarian Emprove Foundation, who work with women survivors of domestic abuse.
The project is called The Stories that Make Us: Giving a voice to women survivors, and finding new models for creative intervention.</description></item><item><title>Education in Post-Coup Myanmar</title><link>https://www.windandbones.com/blog/education-myanmar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.windandbones.com/blog/education-myanmar/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a few new projects recently, including a collaboration with Parami University in Myanmar. We were writers in residence at Parami back in 2018-2019, and after the military coup of February 1st this year, we&amp;rsquo;ve been deeply preoccupied with the unfolding situation over there.</description></item><item><title>Looking for Wisdom: A New Collaboration for Wind&amp;Bones</title><link>https://www.windandbones.com/blog/looking-for-wisdom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.windandbones.com/blog/looking-for-wisdom/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re delighted that Looking for Wisdom, the philosophy-by-email project run by Dr Will Buckingham, is now a part of Wind&amp;amp;Bones. At Wind&amp;amp;Bones, we believe that creative writing and creative thinking have the power to change the world.</description></item><item><title>Why Wind&amp;Bones?</title><link>https://www.windandbones.com/blog/why-wind-and-bones/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 15:28:43 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.windandbones.com/blog/why-wind-and-bones/</guid><description>When we set up Wind&amp;amp;Bones back in 2018, we wanted a name that reflected our vision of writing, creativity and social change. And after a lot of discussion, eventually we came up with Wind&amp;amp;Bones.</description></item><item><title>'Hello, Stranger' hits the shops this July</title><link>https://www.windandbones.com/blog/hello-stranger/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 15:28:43 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.windandbones.com/blog/hello-stranger/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re delighted that our very own Will Buckingham&amp;rsquo;s Hello, Stranger: How We Find Connection in a Disconnected World is coming out from Granta this July 1st.
Will&amp;rsquo;s book brings together insights from philosophy, anthropology, history and literature to explore how our traditions of meeting with strangers can mitigate the issues of our time.</description></item><item><title>Creativity on the Margins of Academia</title><link>https://www.windandbones.com/blog/creativity-margins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 15:28:43 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.windandbones.com/blog/creativity-margins/</guid><description>The other week, we had the pleasure of sitting down for a long Zoom chat about creativity with scholar, travel-writer and researcher Dr Tim Hannigan. Tim works for Dublin City University on their DCU CREDNE — Forging Creativity project.</description></item><item><title>Writing, Pleasure &amp; the Myth of the Suffering Artist</title><link>https://www.windandbones.com/blog/writing-and-pleasure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 15:28:43 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.windandbones.com/blog/writing-and-pleasure/</guid><description>At Wind&amp;amp;Bones, one myth we’re keen to dispel is the myth of the suffering artist. One of the things we do when working with writers is help them find ways to seek out delight and pleasure in their writing.</description></item></channel></rss>