<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creativity on 滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/creativity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Creativity on 滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/creativity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wind&amp;Bones in Taiwan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wind-and-bones-taiwan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wind-and-bones-taiwan/</guid>
      <description>This August, we&amp;rsquo;ll be packing our bags, and heading over to Taiwan. We were last in Taiwan four years ago, on a short visit from Myanmar, and we found ourselves smitten. In particular, while in Tainan (our favourite Taiwanese city), we visited the National Museum of Taiwan Literature, and we were enormously impressed by the nuanced and thoughtful take on the ways in which literature can act as a driver of positive social change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dragon-Carving Updates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dragon-carving-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dragon-carving-updates/</guid>
      <description>Our Dragon-Carving for Writers Project is well underway. In this project, we are exploring the contemporary uses of Liu Xie&amp;rsquo;s medieval Chinese classic, the Wenxin diaolong (文心雕龍), or The Literary Mind and the Carving of Dragons.&#xA;Last month, we held our workshop with our brilliant writers — Dr Sipei Lu 陆思培, Ningli Deng 邓宁立, Zhenhao Shi 史镇豪, Dr Hannah Stevens, Yuhang Zhang 张煜航, and Will Buckingham. We talked about three chapters from Liu&amp;rsquo;s book, exploring the text&amp;rsquo;s philosophical underpinnings, insights into the craft of writing, and discussion of the writer&amp;rsquo;s life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Countering Harmful Stories With Better Stories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/countering-harmful-stories-with-better-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/countering-harmful-stories-with-better-stories/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we were at the British Ambassador&amp;rsquo;s Residence in Sofia for a fundraising event with the Emprove Foundation for our Awakening Between the Lines Project. Here&amp;rsquo;s the speech we wrote for the event.&#xA;Good evening. I&amp;rsquo;m Will Buckingham, co-director of Wind&amp;amp;Bones, and over there is my colleague and Wind&amp;amp;Bones co-director Hannah Stevens. Wind&amp;amp;Bones is a social enterprise now based in Scotland, and we run projects at the intersection of writing, creativity and social change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At the National Gallery, Sofia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/awakening/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/awakening/</guid>
      <description>Next Monday, we&amp;rsquo;re back in Bulgaria to see the exhibition from our project with the Emprove Foundation, working with survivors of domestic abuse on telling and sharing micro-stories. We intensively workshopped a series of stories with a group of fifteen talented women survivors, and artists have been commissioned to produce artworks inspired by the stories. These artworks are the subject of an exhibition that is currently running in The National Gallery of Bulgaria Kvadrat 500.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wind&amp;Bones CIC are now Scottish</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/scotland/</guid>
      <description>Today, we&amp;rsquo;ve been celebrating the fact that Wind&amp;amp;Bones is now a thoroughly Scottish social enterprise. As we are here in Dundee for the long term, we decided to move our business from England to Scotland. This is easier said than done, as companies cannot be straightforwardly moved over the border. But with the help of the brilliant people at Senscot Legal, we&amp;rsquo;ve managed to work round the problem.&#xA;We&amp;rsquo;ve changed the name of our old CIC to Wind&amp;amp;Bones (England), and we&amp;rsquo;ve set up a new CIC called simply Wind&amp;amp;Bones, registered in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Wind&amp;Bones?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-wind-and-bones/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-wind-and-bones/</guid>
      <description>When we set up Wind&amp;amp;Bones back in 2018, we wanted a name that reflected our vision of writing, creativity and social change. And after a lot of discussion, eventually we came up with Wind&amp;amp;Bones.&#xA;But what&amp;rsquo;s in a name? And why are we called this? Is one of us &amp;ldquo;Wind&amp;rdquo; and one of us &amp;ldquo;Bones&amp;rdquo;? Are these our secret superhero names? Alas, no! But the real story is fun and interesting too, and it goes back to medieval China.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Hello, Stranger&#39; hits the shops this July</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-stranger/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 15:28:43 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-stranger/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re delighted that our very own Will Buckingham&amp;rsquo;s Hello, Stranger: How We Find Connection in a Disconnected World is coming out from Granta this July 1st.&#xA;Will&amp;rsquo;s book brings together insights from philosophy, anthropology, history, and literature to explore how our traditions of meeting with strangers can mitigate the issues of our time. Taking in stories of loneliness, exile, and friendship from classical times to the modern day, and alighting in adapting communities from Birmingham to Myanmar, Hello, Stranger asks: how do we set aside our instinctive xenophobia – fear of outsiders – and embrace our equally natural philoxenia – love of strangers and newness?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing, Pleasure &amp; the Myth of the Suffering Artist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/writing-and-pleasure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/writing-and-pleasure/</guid>
      <description>At Wind&amp;amp;Bones, one myth we’re keen to dispel is the myth of the suffering artist. One of the things we do when working with writers is help them find ways to seek out delight and pleasure in their writing. Because once you have pleasure and delight, you have energy and life, and when you have energy and life, you are already half-way to creating something worthwhile.&#xA;Of course, writing can be difficult (tell us about it).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspirations - Maisie Chan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/inspirations-maisie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/inspirations-maisie/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we’re featuring the fabulous Maisie Chan. Read our wide-ranging interview about writing, representation, the ongoing harms of orientalism, and the dedication it takes to be a damn good storyteller.&#xA;Hello, Maisie. It’s great to talk to you. We’re particularly excited because you are the first writer in our Inspirations series, where we feature writers committed to using their words to make the world a better place. This is a really exciting time to be talking to you because you’ve got not one, but two books coming out in the coming few months: Danny Chung Does Not Do Maths (Piccadilly Press), published in the USA as Danny Chung Sums it Up (Amulet Books), and Tiger Warrior: Attack of the Dragon King (Orchard Books).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EmpathEAST talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/empatheast-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/empatheast-talk/</guid>
      <description>We were invited to EmpathEAST in Plovdiv in 2019 to talk about our work at Wind&amp;amp;Bones. So we gave a talk, telling the story of Wind&amp;amp;Bones up to that point.&#xA;Intro [Hannah] Hello!&#xA;We’re delighted to be here at EmpathEAST 2019, and excited to be working together over the next few days.&#xA;It’s also great to be in the lovely city of Plovdiv and to be getting a sense of the history, the cultural richness and the energy of 2019’s European Capital of Culture.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
