<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Festival on Wind&amp;Bones</title>
    <link>https://www.windandbones.com/tags/festival/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Festival on Wind&amp;Bones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.windandbones.com/tags/festival/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Food Done Right, in Waterford, Ireland</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/food-done-right-in-waterford-ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/food-done-right-in-waterford-ireland/</guid>
      <description>The Waterford Harvest Festival kicks off this September in Waterford, Ireland. Run by the brilliant social enterprise GIY, the festival is a three-day celebration of “food done right”, an exploration of food, heritage, and sustainability.&#xA;At Wind&amp;amp;Bones, we&amp;rsquo;re immensely excited to have been invited to be writers in residence at the festival. So on the 10th and 11th of September, we&amp;rsquo;ll be over in Ireland, setting up a story farm. We&amp;rsquo;ll be inviting members of the public to plant the seeds of new stories, and to watch them grow in new and surprising directions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stories Galore At the Dandelion Festival</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/dandelion-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/dandelion-weekend/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, we spent three days in an unexpectedly sunny Glasgow at the Dandelion Festival, a part of the UK-wide Unboxed Festival.&#xA;Dandelion is about deepening our relationship with the natural world, about the joy of growing, and about thinking more deeply about where our food comes from.&#xA;So over the course of the weekend, we were in a potting shed — a little wooden hut — asking people to share their own stories about food: the food they love, the food they hate, the food they like to cook, the food that has caused them to fall in and out of love, the food that reminds them of home.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
