<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eng on 滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/eng/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eng on 滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 01:15:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/eng/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Down the Generations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/down-the-generations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 01:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/down-the-generations/</guid>
      <description>It was my father who taught me to cook. In my family he prepared meals for all of us — breakfast, lunch and dinner. This is very different from a traditional Asian family.&#xA;The reason my father started to cook was because he wanted to reproduce the dishes made by his father, our grandpa. My father&amp;rsquo;s father passed away in my father&amp;rsquo;s early childhood. I never knew him.&#xA;Since learning why my father cooked, I have asked him to teach me some basic cooking skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>我媽媽的越南菜 | My Mother&#39;s Vietnamese Food</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vietnamese-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 05:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vietnamese-food/</guid>
      <description>我媽媽的越南菜 我的母親來自越南， 所以 當我吃到河粉、法國麵包（越南）、越南春捲時，我就會想起媽媽， 我甚至會去比較， 誰做得比較好吃。&#xA;不過並不是拿我媽做參考，我媽沒有做過河粉給我吃過。或是說：我沒有印象，可能有。反倒是她常做春捲、雞肉稀飯、生菜沙拉。 這三樣沒人能贏過她。&#xA;***— 張芳瑋 ***&#xA;My Mother&amp;rsquo;s Vietnamese Food My mother is from Vietnam, so when I eat phở, bánh mì, or Vietnamese spring rolls, I think of my mum. I even compare who makes them the best. But I don&amp;rsquo;t use my mum as a reference, because my mother has never made me phở to eat. Or, to put it another way, I don&amp;rsquo;t have any recollection of it, but perhaps she did.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blue Eyes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blue-eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blue-eyes/</guid>
      <description>When the waitress began to speak, I looked closely at her face, and I noticed that she had the most unusual eyes.&#xA;I think she wore contact lenses because her eyes were blue, but not a crystal-like, light blue like I usually see at home: they were deep navy, almost purple. And I&amp;rsquo;d never seen eyes like that before.&#xA;— Hannah Stevens</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cat Cake</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cat-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 05:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cat-cake/</guid>
      <description>We were walking home late one evening when I saw it. It was a white sign with black writing that read &amp;lsquo;Cake&amp;rsquo; in English.&#xA;There was the image of a cat on the sign and the cat wore sunglasses. As we got closer I could smell the cake. It smelled of cooked sugar, beaten eggs, creamed butter.&#xA;We didn&amp;rsquo;t stop there that night but I want to go back.&#xA;— Hannah Stevens</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culinary Heaven</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/culinary-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 05:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/culinary-heaven/</guid>
      <description>Tainan is a culinary heaven. It flourishes with lively, historic flavours. Every dish echoes the city&amp;rsquo;s rich heritage. Food in Tainan is a vibrant fusion of tradition and innovation on the taste buds.&#xA;Waking up in the morning, have a bowl of hot beef soup from the market, or a soul-soothing bowl of tender minced pork, to make you feel energetic.&#xA;After work in the morning, have a milkfish feast, especially the belly and skin.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
