<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshop on Wind&amp;Bones</title>
    <link>https://www.windandbones.com/tags/workshop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workshop on Wind&amp;Bones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 10:50:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.windandbones.com/tags/workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/%E6%BB%8B%E9%A4%8A%E5%8F%B0%E5%8D%97-nourishing-tainan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 10:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/%E6%BB%8B%E9%A4%8A%E5%8F%B0%E5%8D%97-nourishing-tainan/</guid>
      <description>We ended 2023 with a ten-day residency at the Nanning Literary House (南寧文學·家), where we ran a project called 滋養台南 | Nourishing Tainan. We spent ten days working on our writing, and also working with members of the public to write stories about the things that nourish us: the food that nourishes our bodies, the stories that nourish our spirit, and the ideas that nourish our imagination. You can see the project website here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hot Chocolate - False Perceptions, True Stories</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/hot-chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/hot-chocolate/</guid>
      <description>This July 2023, we worked in Dundee, Scotland with a group of young people, exploring the art of manifesto-writing, and asking how telling truer, better stories can help to counter false perceptions of young people and their lives.&#xA;We explored manifestos from the last one hundred and fifty years, and then collectively wrote a manifesto of our own, one that aimed to get to the heart of the complex, multi-faceted experience of what it means to be a young person today.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stories Galore At the Dandelion Festival</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/dandelion-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/dandelion-weekend/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, we spent three days in an unexpectedly sunny Glasgow at the Dandelion Festival, a part of the UK-wide Unboxed Festival.&#xA;Dandelion is about deepening our relationship with the natural world, about the joy of growing, and about thinking more deeply about where our food comes from.&#xA;So over the course of the weekend, we were in a potting shed — a little wooden hut — asking people to share their own stories about food: the food they love, the food they hate, the food they like to cook, the food that has caused them to fall in and out of love, the food that reminds them of home.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Stories that Make Us - Working With Women Survivors</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/the-stories-that-make-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/the-stories-that-make-us/</guid>
      <description>This November, we&amp;rsquo;re starting a new project with the brilliant Bulgarian Emprove Foundation, who work with women survivors of domestic abuse.&#xA;The project is called The Stories that Make Us: Creative writing with women survivors — finding new models for creative intervention. Over six weeks between November and December this year, we&amp;rsquo;ll be working with a group of women survivors, exploring how storytelling can be used to build community and bring about both individual and social transformation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Education in Post-Coup Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/education-myanmar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windandbones.com/posts/education-myanmar/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a few new projects recently, including a collaboration with Parami University in Myanmar. We were writers in residence at Parami back in 2018-2019, and after the military coup of February 1st this year, we&amp;rsquo;ve been deeply preoccupied with the unfolding situation over there. So we&amp;rsquo;re delighted to be working with Parami University again, running some remote courses via Zoom for students across Myanmar.&#xA;We&amp;rsquo;re running three courses in all.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
